[MUSIC]
Stanford University.
>> All right, well, welcome to Lecture 13 of CS193P,
欢迎来到 CS193P 13课
Winter 2015.
2015冬季
Today, we have three major topics.
今天，我们有三个主题
One which is the Application Lifecycle, which is all about
一个是应用生命周期，这讲的全部都是关于
we talked about the View Controller Lifecycle.
视图控制器生命周期
Where your view controller kinda is born,
在你的视图控制器生成的地方
does a bunch of things and then, dies.
同时有许多东西产生，然后消亡
Well, the same things happen for the whole application.
在整个应用程序中也发生同样的事情
So we'll talk about that.
因此我们将讨论这个
And then, I'm going to talk about Core Motion,
然后，我们将讲 Core Motion
which is figuring out what the device is doing.
这个是找出设备在做什么
Gyro, and accelerometer, magnetometers,
陀螺仪，加速器，地磁仪
all that business.
类似那样的东西
And then, I'm going to talk about persistence,
然后，我将要讲解持久化
which is making things be stored on the internal hard
就是把数据存储在你的设备中的
disk of your device.
内置硬盘
Of course, it's flash memory, but
当然，这是闪存，但
basically it acts a hard disk, a Unix file system even.
基本上它扮演了硬盘的角色，设置一个 Unix 文件系统
So we talk about how we do that.
因此，我们将讲解我们如何实现这些
All right, so let's jump right
让我们从应用生命周期
into the application life cycle.
开始
But we first, I need to give you a little side
但首先，我需要给你们一小点
lecture here on NSNotification.
关于 NSNotification 方面的课程
And we actually saw this briefly
实际上，当我讲解键盘时我们看到
when I was talking about the keyboards.
过这个
And you get this notification when the keyboards show up.
当键盘出现时你们得到这个通知
But I decided I'm going to take a couple of slides here
但我决定将带几个幻灯片
and just talk about NSNotification and
然后只讲 NSNotification
how it works.
还有它怎么运作
Because it's actually a fairly important part.
因为它真的是很重要的一部分
Not fairly important,
不是很重要
somewhat important part of the MVC model.
MVC 模式中比较重要的一部分
So if you remember back to our MVC slides.
因此如果你们回忆起我们的 MVC 幻灯片
I had a little kinda thing that looked like a radio
我有一个小东西，它看起来像一个
station.
电台
It was broadcasting from the model.
它从模型中被发送出去
And then the controller would tune into that radio station
然后控制器将调频到电台
to find out that changes were happening in the model.
找出在模型中所发生的变化
Well that's,
one of the things that make that happen is NSNotification.
让这些事情发生的其中之一是 NSNotification
And so, it's the radio station or
它是电台或者
one of the ways of doing the radio station in MVC.
在 MVC 中处理电台的途径之一
And it's really for model to controller communication or
这实际是模型到控制器的通讯或者
sometimes global to controller.
有时是全局对控制器
Cuz sometimes things happen globally in your entire
因为有时事情发生你的整个应用的全局
application, as we're gonna see in the demo today.
正如我们今天要看到的 demo
And you need to kinda broadcast that this global
你需要广播这个全局的
thing is happening.
事情正在发生
And then particular view controllers might
然后特定视图控制器可能
be interested in that.
对这有兴趣
They'll sign up to listen to that radio station and
他们将注册监听电台然后
they'll find out that global thing has happened.
他们讲发现所发生的全局的事情
So how does it work?
这是如何工作的？
It's super simple.
它超级简单
There is a class called NSNotificationCenter
这里有一个类叫做 NSNotificationCenter
it has a class function called defaultCenter.
它有一个类函数叫做 defaultCenter
You get that,
你们得到这个
that's this kinda shared notification center.
它类似共享消息中心
And you just send a message to it called addObserver
你只需发送一个消息给它，它叫做
for name.
addObserverForName
And you specify the name of the radio station you
然后你指定你想收听的
wanna listen to.
电台的名字
Okay.
It has a couple other arguments which are,
它有其他几个参数，这些是
is object.
对象
Object is who's the broadcaster.
Object 就是发送广播者
Who are you interested in broadcasts on this
你们谁对这个电台发送的
radio station from?
广播感兴趣
And you can just put nil there if you're interested
你可以置 nil 值，如果你对该电台
when anybody broadcasts on that radio station.
中任何人发送的广播都感兴趣的话
But sometimes you'll specify I'm only interested if
但有时，你要指定只对这个
this guy broadcasts on this radio station.
电台中的这个广播感兴趣
And then, notice that there's a queue.
然后，注意这里有一个队列
And then a closure right after it.
然后它后面有一个闭包
Okay. Queue and a closure.
队列是一个闭包
So the queue is just saying
因此这个队列只是
what queue you want after this closure to be executed on.
这个闭包执行之后你想要哪个队列
I think if you put nil there you get I think
我想如果你在这个放 nil，你将得到
the main queue.
主队列
Possibly the current queue, but maybe the main queue.
也可能是当前队列，或者主队列
But might as well just put it in there.
但可能也只是把它放在那里
Now notice NSOperationQueue,
现在注意 NSOperationQueue
I briefly mentioned that earlier in the quarter too.
我刚才简要提到了这个
You're used to dispatch_queue_t, that thing.
你们熟悉 dispatch_queue_t
NSOperationQueue is just kinda an object oriented API on top
NSOperationQueue 类似一个在分发工作中
of the whole dispatching business.
顶端的面向对象的 API
GCD, Grand Central Dispatch.
GCD，Grand Central Dispatch
So, it's very thin layer looks almost exactly the same.
因此，它是非常轻的一层，看起来几乎是一样的
But object oriented APIs usually will ask for
但面向对象的 API 们通常会请求
a NSOperationQueue.
NSOperationQueue
That has a couple of class functions like main queue,
有许多类函数，比如主队列
where you can get the main queue.
在那里你可以获取主队列
And you can create your own queues by just saying
你可以创建你自己的队列
NSOperationQueue open parentheses
NSOperationQueue 左括号
close parentheses to initialize it.
右括号进行初始化
So anyway, specify the queue you want.
不管怎样，指定你想要的队列
And then, what's gonna happen is,
然后，将要发生的是
if anyone broadcasts on that radio station,
如果有人在那个电台上发送广播
the following closure is going to be executed.
下面的这个闭包将被执行
And that closure only has one argument there,
这个闭包只有一个参数
which is an NSNotification.
即 NSNotification
That NSNotification has a few fields in it.
NSNotification 里面有几个字段
But the really only interesting field is
但真正有趣的字段是
the field called userInfo.
userInfo
And the userInfo is just a dictionary.
userInfo 是一个字典
The dictionary of kinda old style, Objective-C dictionary
这个字典有点老的风格，Objective-C 字典
with NSObject as the keys, AnyObject as the values.
keys 是 NSObject， values 是 AnyObject
And every radio station it broadcasts
任何一个它广播的电台
is going to have kinda different userInfo.
都有点不一样的 userInfo
And when you go and look at the documentation for
当你开始，查找关于电台的
that radio station.
文档
Which is going to tell you the name,
这将告诉你名字
that you're going to addObserver for name.
就是你将调用的 addObserverForName 中的名字.
It's also going to tell you what it provides you in
它也将告诉你 userInfo 中
it's userInfo.
提供了哪些信息
Okay, so let's look at an example of doing this.
让我们看一个例子来做这个
So you can kinda make it more concrete.
你们可以将这个变得更具体化
Which is finding out when the user changes their text size.
这个将发现用户改变他们的文本大小
So in Settings, here I'm just in Settings on a phone.
在设置里，这里我只是在一个手机中的设置中
If I go to General Settings right here and
如果我到通用设置
I go down to Accessibility, then I go down to Larger Text.
然后我到下层的 Accessibility，然后我到下一层的更大文本
You can see there's this slider here, which I can
你们可以看到这里的滑动条，通过这个我可以
use to set the size of the text that I want in my apps.
设置我的应用里面的文本大小
Well, if you have an app that has text in it, or
如果你们有一个有文本的应用，或者
that is sized depending on the setting of this,
它的大小依赖于这个设置
you might want to react to that.
你可能要采取相应的措施
Well the way you get notified of that is you get
你得到这个通知的方式是你
a broadcast on a radio station.
在一个电台收到广播
The radio station is called the UI content size category
这个电台叫做 UI content size 类别
did change notification radio station, 'kay?
确实改变了电台的通知，对吧？
That's the name of it.
这是它的名字
Radio station is just something I use.
电台就是我使用的东西
It's not really called radio station, okay?
实际上它不叫电台
So, that's the name of it, and
因此，这是它的名字
it's sent out by the UIApplication object.
它是通过 UIApplication 对象发送的
Of which there's this one shared application,
这是一个共享的应用
which you get by calling that method right there,
你通过调用那个方法来获得
sharedApplication.
共享应用
And I wanna hear about this on the main queue, okay?
我想在主队列中收到这个？
So I have my block.
所以我有自己的 block
It gets this notification argument.
它取得这个通知的参数
Inside the notification argument there's the userInfo.
在通知参数中，这是 userInfo
And it turns out this radio station, when it broadcasts,
结果是这个电台，当它广播时
the userInfo contains the
userInfo 包含
UIContentSizeCategoryNewValue- Key.
UIContentSizeCategoryNewValue 键
And if I get that key out of the dictionary,
如果我从字典中取出这个键
the value I get is the size.
我得到的值便是（文本）大小
And there's a bunch of enums or strings for
还有很多枚举或者字符串
it like UIContentSizeCategorySmall or
比如 UIContentSizeCategorySmall 或者
UIContentSizeExtraLarge or whatever.
UIContentSizeExtraLarge 或任何其它的
So that's how you get it.
这就是你怎么得到它
And so this could come at anytime because the user could
这个可能随时都会广播，因为用户
go to settings and set this at anytime.
可能在任何时候在设置中设置这个值
And you'll just get this closure executed.
然后这个闭包将被执行
And it can be executed multiple times once you
一旦你注册这个，它可能
register this.
被执行很多次
Then it's going to get called whenever that thing changes.
当文本大小改变时这个都会被调用
That make sense?
有道理吧？
So there's a lot of radio stations in iOS.
在 iOS 中有很多电台
We're going to talk about Core Data,
我们将谈谈 Core Data
object-oriented database for example.
举个例子，面向对象的数据库
That got some very important notifications where it tells
当你的数据库中有数据改变时
you that things have changed in the database.
你会收到一些非常重要的通知
That's the classic model.
这是经典的模型
Communicating to the controllers.
和控制器通讯
And I'm going to do a little demo where we're gonna
我要做个小例子，当我们
broadcast on our own radio station.
在我们的电台中广播
And I'm missing a slide in here,
这里我少了一个幻灯片
I noticed, which is how to broadcast.
我注意到了，就是怎样广播
But broadcasting is very easy,
但广播是非常简单的
you just create one of these NSNotification objects.
你只需要创建这些 NSNotification 对象中的一个
And then, you ask the defaultCenter,
然后，你询问 defaultCenter
postNotification.
defaultCenter
So it's a method in the defaultCenter called
这个是 defaultCenter 中一个叫做
postNotification, you just give it a notification,
postNotification 的方法，你只需给它一个通知
it'll broadcast it, simple as that.
它将广播它，就这样简单
So we'll see that in the demo as well.
我们也会在例子中看到这个
Okay, so that's notifications.
这就是通知
And they're important in the application
他们在应用的生命周期中
life cycle as you're going to see.
很重要，马上你们就会看到了
So let's talk about the application life cycle.
让我们谈谈应用生命周期
Really your application gets launched.
当你的应用启动时
The user is using it.
用户就在使用它
Then the user clicks to go to a different app.
然后用户切换到另一个不同应用
And they come back to your app.
然后他们再返回到你的应用
Maybe, your app starts using a lot of memory.
也许，你的应用启动时使用了很多内存
Or does something else, that the system doesn't like.
或者做了其他系统不喜欢的事情
Or the phone runs out of power.
或者手机没电了
And you get killed, okay?
你的应用被杀掉了
And so, that's kinda the life cycle.
这就是生命周期
And you go back and
然后你的应用在前台
forth between being in the foreground,
来回使用
which means the user's using you.
也就是用户在使用你的应用
And being in the background,
然后在后台
which means the user's using something else.
这意味中用户在使用其他的应用
That's the green versus blue in this picture.
这就是这张图中绿色与蓝色部分
But you transition from these states in a very orderly
但你在这些状态中以一个非常有序的方式
fashion.
过渡
And we're going to talk about that transition.
我们将谈谈这个转变
So.
In the green area, so
在绿色区域
you start out not running, that's at the top.
开始应用没有运行，这就是顶部
Obviously, your app is not even running at all.
显然，你的应用甚至都没有运行
Okay? Then you move to this
然后你移到这个
foreground state where you're, you start out inactive,
前台状态，你开始活跃
which means you're running.
这意味着你开始运行
Your code is running, but
你的代码正在运行，但是
you're not getting any UI events.
你并没有得到任何 UI 事件
Okay. You're not really displayed
实际上你没有在屏幕上
onscreen and getting touch events yet.
显示，也没有得到触摸事件
But you started up, you started running.
但你启动了，你开始运行
Then you move to this state where you're active,
然后你移到这个状态，在这里你是活跃的
which is your view controller is on screen,
这里你的控制器将在屏幕上显示
it's getting touch events.
你得到了触摸事件
This is normal mode.
这是正常的模式
Okay?
This is what you're used to.
这就是你已经习惯的
This is where you are most of the time that your code
当你的代码运行时，这就是你大部分时候所在
is running.
的地方
But if the user clicks on another app,
但当用户点击另一个应用
then you can move to this state called the background
你可以移到这个叫做后台的状态
where you'll run for a very brief period.
在这里你运行很短的时间
I could be incredibly brief and
我可以难以置信的简单
then your code just stops running.
然后你的代码将停止运行
Now you're not, you haven't been killed, but
现在你没有，你的应用还没被杀掉
your code is not running.
但你的代码没有运行
So there's nothing you can do in this state.
在这个状态下你什么也做不了
Now when you transition to this background,
当你切换到后台时
you can ask for a little more time.
你可以请求多一点的时间
But if you don't, you kinda quickly go to the state
但如果你没有，你将很快转换到
where you're not running.
你没运行的状态
Okay.
That's the suspended state down at the bottom.
这是在底部的挂起状态
So you stay in this blue area for a short amount of time,
因此你在蓝色区域停留很短的时间
this background state.
这个后台状态
Now you can be put into this blue area other times too.
你可能在其他时候被放置在这个蓝色区域
Like there's a way to tell the system, hey,
比如有种方式告诉系统
I want to wake up every once in a while and
我想要隔一段时间就被唤醒
go and fetch something from the internet.
去从网络中请求一些数据
So that when the user does launch my app or
因此当用户启动我的应用或者
bring it to the foreground,
把它带到前台时
I have got the latest information for them.
我已经为他们获取了最新的信息
Okay?
So the system can wake you up in the background.
系统可以在后台唤醒你
You'll run for a very short amount of time while you go do
你可以运行非常短的时间，当你
this little fetch and then you go back to suspended state.
需要获取一些数据，然后你回到挂起状态
Okay?
Now, while you're in the suspended state, okay?
当你在挂起状态时
Down here and your code is not running at all.
在下面的这里，你的代码根本没有运行
None of your code is being executed and
你的代码并没有被执行
you could be killed from here.
你的应用可能在这里被杀死
So you wanna be careful when you move from the background
因此你需要小心，当你从后台状态转换到
state to the suspended state to clean everything up and
挂起状态，保证清理了所有东西并且
get everything ready for your death.
做好应用挂掉的准备
Okay?
Cuz you might get killed.
因为你的应用可能被杀死
That's rare to get killed, but you could.
应用很少会被杀死，但却是可能的
Okay?
So you have to think of being in suspended state as
所以你要考虑到在挂起状态，当
I'm suspended and I could be killed at any moment.
我的应用挂起时，它随时可能被杀死
So [LAUGH] you can't run any code when you're gonna be
当你的应用被杀死时，你不能运行任何代码
killed, so you better clean that up when you're passing
所以你最好清理应用，当你在后台
through the back, creating through a background.
时，在后台创建一些东西
Okay.
So let's talk about how you find out,
让我们谈谈你如何发现
as you move through and you can only pass along the orange
当你转换状态，你只能沿着这些桔色的线
lines to get from these states.
转换到这些状态
Okay? So
when you come out of the background,
当你从后台返回时
you briefly will be inactive and then go to active.
你从短暂的非活跃状态转换到活跃状态
Right?
So let's talk about how we pass through.
让我们谈谈如何做这种转换
So launching is just a matter of moving into the foreground,
启动只是转换到前台的事情
briefly inactive and then you're active.
短暂的不活跃，然后你的应用变成活跃状态
That's your application being launched.
这样你的应用被启动了
Switching to another app is you started out active,
切换到另一个应用，你不再活跃
you go inactive for a moment.
一会你就变成不活跃
You come around, you're in background for a moment and
你的应用苏醒过来，当其他的应用在运行时
then you go suspended while the other app gets to run.
一会你就在后台然后转换到挂起状态
Okay?
So that's the flow of switching to another app.
这就是切换到另一个应用的过程
Okay?
Now every time you make a transition along these orange
每次你沿着这些桔色的线做
lines, you get notified.
转换，你都会收到通知
So let's talk about, for example, own's,
让我们谈谈，比如，我们自己的应用
of course killed.
当然被杀掉
You can be killed, your code won't run.
你可能被杀掉，你的代码不会运行
Be careful, be ready.
准备好，小心点
All right. So let's talk about
让我们谈谈
these transitions.
这些转换
So right there, the little yellow circle is talking about
在那里，这个小黄圆圈
moving into this inactive state from not running.
从未运行转换到这个不活跃的状态
Okay? When that happens,
当这发生时
you get sent this message to your application delegate.
你发送这个消息给你的应用代理
You remember that AppDelegate file that I always drag out of
你们记得这个 AppDelegate 文件吗？每次在我的例子开始时
the way every single time at the beginning of my demos?
我经常把它拖拽到其他地方
Well, that file is an interesting file.
这个文件是个有趣的文件
It actually has a class in it called your AppDelegate.
实际上它有一个类，叫做 AppDelegate
Your AppDelegate is the delegate of your UI
你的 AppDelegate 是你的 UI 应用对象的
application object and the UI application object,
代理，是 UI 应用对象
you never subclass it.
你从不继承它
If you want to customize its behavior, you do so
如果你需要定制它的行为，你在 AppDelegate
by implementing methods in the AppDelegate.
中实现方法
So one of the methods you can get sent,
其中一个方法，你可以发送
one of the delegate protocol methods for an application
应用代理其中一个代理协议方法是
delegate is application did finish launching with options.
application didFinishLaunchingWithOptions
And that gives you a dictionary,
这个方法给你一个字典
which we'll talk about in a second.
一会我们将谈到这个
And so that, so
因此
you're always gonna know the first time you startup from
你总是第一时间知道你的应用
not being running at all to being in this inactive state.
从未运行转换到这个不活跃状态
Now what's in the [INAUDIBLE] by the way,
[INAUDIBLE] 是什么，顺便说下
you get all these messages sent to you to your
你在你的 AppDelegate 中获得所有
AppDelegate, but you also a get a notification.
这些信息，但你也得到一个通知
That we were talking about in previous slide.
就是我们在上个幻灯片中谈到的
So you can sign up to listen to the radio station.
你可以注册收听这个电台
UI application did finish launching notification and
UIApplicationDidFinishLauningNotification 然后
when you launch, you'll get a message on the radio station.
当你启动时，你将在电台中得到一个消息
Now that's only gonna happen once per launching of your
显然，这只会在你每次启动应用时
app, obviously.
发生
And the user info in that notification,
在通知中的 userInfo
of course contains the same dictionary that's being passed
当然包含了它在这个方法中将被传递的
to this method.
字典
Okay?
So what's the difference between these two?
这两个有什么区别？
Well, you know, if you put the code in your AppDelegate to
你们知道的，当你在 AppDelegate 中写代码
find out that you've been launched, you know,
来判断你是否被启动了，你们知道的
it kinda has to be global code.
这类似于全局代码
Right? Because you're just,
对吧？因为你刚刚
it's in you AppDelegate, it's kind of in this global place.
在你的 AppDelegate 中，在这个全局的地方
Whereas if a particular view controller wanted to find out,
如果有一个特别的视图控制器需要被发现
oh, I just launched.
我（控制器）刚刚启动
Okay?
It can have its code in itself, so
它内部可以有自己的代码
it can be more object oriented.
它可以更面向对象
Right?
It can have its reaction to launching be just in itself,
它可以在内部对启动做出反应
it doesn't have to be talking to some global thing
它不需要和全局的东西进行通信
like the AppDelegate.
比如 AppDelegate
And in general, you wanna be careful about the AppDelegate,
一般的，使用 AppDelegate 时你需要小心点
cuz it is a global resource.
因为它是全局资源
And as you know, from all your computer science training.
你们知道的，在你们的计算机科学知识中
Globals can be bad.
全局是不好的
Okay?
Globals are generally not the way you wanna communicate
全局通常不是你想交流信息的方式
information, but some things are global.
当有些东西是全局的
Okay?
Like when we talk about core motion and the phone,
比如当我们谈论 core motion 和手机
there's only one gyro, there's only one accelerometer.
只有一个陀螺仪，只有一个加速计
That is global, okay?
这就是全局
To your entire device, certainly to your entire app.
你的整个设备，当然，你的整个应用
Okay.
So some things are global, but
因此有些东西是全局的
don't use global variables basically through your
但别使用全局变量，在你的
AppDelegate to circumvent that.
AppDelegate 中别使用
All right.
So what's in this past dictionary,
在这个传递的字典中有什么
this dictionary that you get?
你获取的这个字典？
It's basically gonna tell you why you were launched.
基本上它会告诉你你为什么被启动了
Okay?
Cuz you can get launched for a lot of reasons.
因为你可能由于很多原因被启动
The user might have just clicked on you, okay?
用户可能只是点击了你的应用
And launch you, but
然后启动了应用
it might be a situation where someone air dropped a file of
但也可能是这种情况，有人通过 AirDrop 传送了一个
a certain type that you know how to open.
你知道怎么打开的文件
And the system will launch you to open that file,
因此系统将启动你来打开这个文件
which is kinda cool.
这非常酷
We're gonna hopefully do air drop in our demo today.
我们将在今天的例子中讲解 AirDrop
You might have setup some boundaries, and
你们可能创建了一些边界
your phone moved into that part of the world.
当你们的手机移动到这个世界的这个部分
So, it's possible to actually setup s big region and say,
实际上，有可能创建一个很大的区域
when this device comes in this region, run my app.
当这个设备到达这个区域时，运行我的应用
Okay?
And if your app is not running, it will get launched.
如果你的应用没有运行，它将被启动
Okay?
To go deal with the fact that you just moved near the dry
处理这些情况，当你移动到干洗机附近时
cleaners or
或者
whatever you put in there as one of your regions.
你的区域中的任何一个地方
In iOS8, you can start an activity like editing a file
在 iOS8，你可以开始一个活动，在一个设备中
on one device, like your Mac and then walk out the door and
编辑一个文件，比如你的 Mac，然后走出门
pull out your phone and keep editing it.
然后取出你的手机，继续编辑这个文件
Okay? So,
it's kind of like you can continue activities, so
这有点类似于你的活动可以持续性地进行
you might get launched to continue an activity.
你可能由于继续一个活动而被启动
Okay? You could get launched,
你可能被启动
because a push notification arrives.
由于一个推送通知到达
Do you know what a push notification is?
你们知道什么是推送通知吗？
Basically, this service where third parties can send you
基本上，使用这个服务，第三方可以给你
notifications.
发送通知
So for example, if you're playing a game,
比如，如果你在玩一个游戏
maybe its a turn based game and its your turn.
它可能是一个轮流制的游戏，现在轮到你
You can go to push notification and
你可以在推送通知
it might launch the game to take your turn.
它可能启动这个游戏开始
Okay?
So a lot of reasoning could be launched and
有很多原因都可以启动应用
that dictionary is going to contain information about why.
这个字典将包含为何启动的信息
All right?
Now, it used to be that an application didn't finish
它习惯于应用启动并没有带
launching with options, you would build your UI.
options，你可以创建你的 UI
So you'd instantiate a split view,
你要初始化一个 split 视图
you'd instantiate a navigation controller.
你必须初始化一个 navigation controller
You'd put in there with a master.
你要在里面放一个 master
You'd put to create your view controller.
你需要在其中创建你的视图控制器
Okay.
We don't do any of that anymore and
我们不要再做任何更多的事情
when you're searching on the internet for how to do things,
当你在网上搜索如何实现一些东西时
you're probably gonna find some old stuff that says,
你很有可能找到一些旧的说法
put this in application did finish launching with options.
把这些放在 ApplicationDidFinishLaunchingWithOptions
I'm generally a fan of not putting that kind
基本上我不会把这类代码放在
of code in application did finish launching with options.
ApplicationDidFinishLaunchingWithOptions
It's really not what it's for.
它不是为了做这些事情
It's more for
它是为了
handling all these other kind of global events,
处理所有这些另外的全局事件
like somebody wants you to open a file or whatever.
比如有人希望你打开一个文件或者其他的任何东西
Okay?
It's not where you build your UI.
你不应该在这里创建你的 UI
You build your UI in your storyboard as much
你尽可能在你的 storyboard 中
as possible.
创建 UI
All right?
Okay.
So now you are moving, so you've been active.
现在你移动了，你已经处于活跃状态
Okay? We haven't talked about this
我们还没谈到这个变成
getting too active.
活跃状态了
But let's say you are active now.
但让我们说现在你是活跃的
And someone clicks on another app.
然后有人点击了另一个应用
And you go to this inactive state.
然后你到了这个不活跃的状态
You go from active to inactive.
你从活跃变成不活跃
You're going to get application will
你将取得 applicationWillResignActive
resign active.
Now, what do you want to do in this method,
在这个方法中，你想要做什么
or when you get this notification?
或者什么时候你会收到这个通知？
This is mostly where you want to pause your UI.
大部分时候是在你需要暂停你的 UI
Because you've just gone inactive.
因为你将变成不活跃
Okay?
It might be that someone's going to come right back to
有可能有人返回你的应用
you and you want to continue.
你需要继续
Okay?
So in resign active, you want to pause.
在 ResignActivie 时，你需要暂停
This is I think of as the pause method.
这就是我认为的暂停方法
Okay?
You're going from active,
你将从活跃
where the user is using your to this inactive state, pause.
也就是用户在使用你的应用变成这个不活跃状态，暂停
Okay? Now you might be on your way
你可能在你转变进入
to going to into the background, but
后台的过程中，但
you might not be.
也可能不是
It might just be that a phone call came in.
有可能有个电话进来了
When a phone call comes in, kind of the current
当一个电话进来时，类似当前应用
application gets put in the inactive state,
变成不活跃状态
you answer the call, and
你接了电话
when you're done it goes back to being active again.
当你接完电话，返回到活跃状态
Okay, so you want to pause there.
所以你需要在那里暂停
Now, what about going back to active?
返回到活跃状态会怎样？
So you were paused and
你被暂停了
you transitioned to active, or you were launched and
然后你转变到活跃状态，或者你被启动了
you transitioned all the way to active.
你转变到活跃状态
This is where you want to, kind of, unpause.
这里你想要不暂停
So this is where you
在这里你
would undo whatever you did in Resign.
将撤销你在 Resign 中做的事情
So Resign and BecomeActive obviously are paired.
所以 Resign 和 BecomeActive 显然是一对的
Resign, you can kinda think as pause my state.
Resign，你可以认为暂停我的状态
And BecomeActive, you can think of as resume my state.
而 BecomeActive，你可以认为重新开始我的状态
Now, of course, when you're launching for
当然，当你第一次启动时
the first time, you go through the Inactive state.
你会经历不活跃状态
You never resigned Active, so you never paused.
你从不 resignedActive，所以你从不暂停
So there's never, no reason to resume.
这里永不，也没有理由重新开始
Okay? You still might do some
你仍需要做在那种情况下
of the things you do to resume in that case.
重新开始的一些事情
But obviously that combination can happen.
但显然，这种组合可能发生
All right. So what about this state?
这种状态下会怎样？
So now you've gone to background.
现在你进入后台
So if they clicked on some other app,
如果他们点击其他的应用
you go into the background.
你将进入后台
Remember, you only go in here briefly.
记住，你只短暂地在这里
Okay? This is where you wanna
在这里你需要做好应对危机的
batten down the hatches and prepare for your death.
准备，为你（应用）的死亡做好准备
Okay?
Because you could sit in background for
因为你可能在后台停留了
just a few fractions of a second, go into suspended, and
一秒钟的一点碎片，便进入挂起状态
then you could be killed.
然后你（应用）被杀死了
Okay? Without ever getting chance
甚至没有机会再次
to run again.
运行
So going into the background stage application did enter
所以进入后台状态，applicationDidEnterBackground
background.
That's where you want to batten down the hatches,
在这里你需要做好应对危机的准备
prepare for your own death.
为你（应用）自己的死去做好准备
Save any unsaved information although you should probably
保存任何未保存的信息，即使你很可能
be saving that.
正在保存
Most of you don't.
大部分时候你没有
Most of the things like here if you start off threads to go
这里的大部分事情，如果你开启线程做一些事情
do things like you have a background thread that does
比如你有一个后台进程正在保存
some saving, make sure that thread is finished.
数据，确保这个进程结束了
And it is possible in DidEnterBackground to ask for
在 DidEnterBackground 中是可能请求
more time.
多一些时间
Okay? UI application has a method
UIApplication 有一个方法
which I'm not gonna talk about, but you can basically
这个方法我还没讲到，但你基本上可以
start up a background task and get some more time to run in
启动一个后台任务，然后在你进入挂起状态前
this background stage before you go to suspended.
得到一些更多的时间在后台运行
If you abuse that.
如果你滥用这个方法
OKay?
Like you try to stay active forever, or for many minutes,
例如你试图永远留在活跃状态，或者停留很多分钟
the system will stop granting you that.
系统将阻止让你这么做
Okay? So don't do that.
所以别做这个
System expects you, if you as for more time,
系统期待你，如果你请求多些时间
to quickly get that done with.
快速完成事情
Or to time out whatever you're doing, do something.
或者暂停任何你正在做的事情，做些事情
Because when you go to the background it really wants you
因为当你在后台时，实际上它希望你
to shut up, okay?
停止
Be quite, because some other app is running right now.
保持安静，因为有其他的应用正在运行
Okay, so that did DidEnterBackground.
因此 DidEnterBackground
When you get activated again from the background
当你再次从后台中变成活跃状态
because someone clicked back on you, this is where you can
因为有人点击了你，在这里你可以
un-batten down the hatches, right?
不用为危机做准备
This is where you can open things back.
在这里你可以打开一些东西
Back up a bit.
备份许多
You're back in the foreground, okay?
你返回到前台
Maybe if you had something saved or
也许如果你有些东西在保存或者
you threw away something from the heap,
你从堆中丢掉一些东西
you can load it back up, et cetera.
你可以把它加载回来，等等
So, this is kind of getting yourself back to life
这类似于在应对危机之后返回到
after battening down the hatches, okay?
生存状态
So, that's it.
这就是全部了
That's the cycle.
这就是生命周期
That's how it goes.
这就是它如何运作
The AppDelegate does a lot more things than just that
AppDelegate 处理了很多事情，不仅仅是
cycle.
这个周期
It handles notifications.
它处理通知
It can do this whole thing, a state restoration.
它可以处理全部事情，一个状态存储
So there's a way, kind of a mechanism I will say,
这是一种方式，我将会讲的一种机制
which I don't have time to talk to you about,
这个我没有时间跟你们说更多
where you can essentially, save the state of your UI, so
在这里你大体上可以保存你的 UI 状态
that if you do get killed while you're suspended,
因此如果你在挂起时被杀死了
and you start up again,
然后你再次启动了
you'll start up in exactly the same place you were
你将从你上次所在的地方重启
instead of starting up like a fresh app launch.
而不是全新启动一个应用
So the AppDelegate is how you do all of that.
通过 AppDelegate 你可以做这些
Look that up.
看这上面的
Data protection.
数据保护
There's a mechanism for
这里有一个机制
saying, hey, the data that my app accesses should be
在手机锁定之后，我的应用访问的数据
encrypted whenever the phone is locked.
需要加密
That's great because if someone steals your phone or
这非常棒，因为有人偷了你的手机或者
tries to break into it, all of the data's encrypted.
试图进入系统，所有数据加密了
They can't see your data anyway,
他们不可能看到任何数据
even if they hack into it.
即使他们攻击进入系统
But you need to find out in your AppDelegate when that
但你需要在你的 AppDelegate 检查什么时候
gets turned off and back on, so you can find that out.
它关闭和打开了，所以可以找出它们
Obviously, opening and closing files, right?
显然，打开和关闭文件
Not opening and closing,
不是打开和关闭
opening files yourself, files that you know how to open.
你自己打开文件，你知道怎么打开的文件
The Delegate gets sent a message saying,
代理发送了一条消息，说
please open this URL.
请打开这个 URL
You have to register with the system for
你需要注册系统，什么样
what kind of files you know how to do, and
的文件你知道如何打开
we'll do that in the demo here.
我们要在例子中做这个
But then this application delegate method is going
但这个应用代理方法将请求
to ask you to open it.
你打开它
And then I mentioned background fetching where you
我提到的，在后台获取中
can, essentially, tell the system you want to wake up
大体上，告诉系统你想要隔一段时间
every once in a while and do some work in the background.
就被唤醒，然后在后台做些工作
And that's pretty cool.
这非常酷
Again, you don't want to abuse it, or
再次，你不要滥用这个方法
the system will start saying, wow, that guy's really a pig.
否则系统将开始抱怨，这个家伙真是只猪
Every time I wake him up to run in the background,
每次我在后台唤醒它去运行
he uses all kinds of battery, so
它使用了所有电量
I'm going to stop waking him up so much.
因此我将不再唤醒它这么频繁了
But it can do that.
但它能做这个
So AppDelegate.
因此 AppDelegate
A lot of stuff in there.
那里有很多事情
You can just go look at the documentation for it and
你可以只是查阅文档
see all the things it can do.
看它都能做些什么事情
Now in addition, question?
还有问题吗？
>> Yeah. I was just wondering,
我刚在想
I had an app once which had music, and
我有一个播放音乐的应用
when I pressed the home button or even locked the phone,
当我按下 home 键时，或者锁定了手机
it would still keep playing.
它还可以继续
Shouldn't it be like turning that off?
难道你不应该被关闭吗？
>> Yes, the question is, what if I have a music app and
问题是，如果我有一个音乐应用
I'm playing music and
然后我正在播放音乐
I switch to another app, how does it keep playing?
然后我切换到另一个应用，它是怎么做到继续播放的？
Well, that's one of the cases where you are allowed to be
这是你被允许在后台运行的
running in the background.
一个例子
So that app is running in the background.
因此这个应用在后台运行
And you have to sign up and kind of requisition your app.
你需要注册，你的应用的要求
You have to set a capability to do that.
你需要设置一个能力来实现这个
But you can do it.
但你可以做到这个
And, you know, if your app is a bad citizen and
你知道的，如果你的应用是个不良公民
says it's a music playing app but
它是一个音乐播放应用，但
it's doing other things in the background.
它在后台做了其他事情
Again, if it starts using a lot of battery,
再次，如果它使用了太多的电量
it's gonna get killed.
它将被杀死
Or it's not gonna be given an opportunity.
系统不会给这样一个机会
You might make it to the app store at the beginning.
你可能在开始的时候在应用商店做到了
But eventually they'll pull you if you are abusing
但最后他们会下架你的应用，如果你滥用
the backgrounding mechanisms.
后台机制
Because there are other ways you can, you know.
因为有其他方式你可以，你知道的
Voip apps need to be able to stay in the background,
贵宾应用需要能够留在后台
you're on a phone call.
你在接一个电话
There are reasons to stay live in the background.
他们有理由留在后台
Some people think, IOS not really multi-tasking.
有人认为，iOS 不是真正的多任务
It absolutely is multi-tasking, but
它绝对是多任务，但
it has a philosophy which is the app
它有一个哲学，也就是用户当前
that the user is currently interacting with should get
交互的应用应该得到
almost all of the attention of the device.
设备的绝大部分资源
That's just its philosophy,
这就是它的哲学
which I think is a good philosophy.
我认为这是个好的哲学
So anything that runs in the background,
因此所有在后台运行的东西
has to really keep it quiet.
需要保持安静
But music is one where it can play in the background.
但音乐是个可以在后台播放的应用
So in addition to the Application Delegate,
另外，应用代理
there's the UI application object itself,
这是 UIApplication 对象
which is the shared thing you call this class function
就是你在这个函数 sharedApplication
shared application to get it.
中获取的共享对象
And it manages all the global behavior in your app.
你管理你应用中的所有全局行为
You don't subclass it.
你不用继承这个类
But you can send it a lot of messages to do various
但你可以发送很多信息来做各种
things like open a URL in another app.
事情，比如在另一个应用中打开一个 URL
So we talked about how the delegate is used
我门谈论使用代理在你的应用中
to open a URL in your own app.
打开一个 URL
You can call this method open URL in application,
你可以调用这个方法在应用中打开 URL
and you did that in your last assignment.
你在你们上次作用中做了这个
So you can open URL, and
你可以打开 URL
it will figure out what apps on your device handle that.
然后它将找出你设备上的哪个应用可以处理这个
And it will open that URL up.
然后它将打开这个 URL
You can also register for
你也可以注册推送通知
push notifications or you can schedule local notifications.
或者你可以安排本地通知
So local notifications are just
本地通知是类似于
notifications kind of like push notifications, but
推送通知，但
they're totally local and they're timed.
它们完全是本地的，它们被计时
So you say, send this notification to the user at
你会说，在这个时候发送这个通知给用户
this time and it sends it to them.
然后它发送通知给他们了
And then push notifications, as we've talked about before,
然后推送通知，就是我们之前谈过的
are these things that come over the network when it's
通过网络发送的东西，当你
your turn to play your game, or whatever.
继续玩你的游戏，或者其他任何事情
So you can register to receive those in scheduled
因此你可以通过 UIApplication 注册接受一些本地
notifications locally using UIApplication.
计划性的通知
If you're doing this background fetching thing,
如果你做这个后台获取工作
there's a very important function called
有一个非常重要的方法叫做
setMinimumBackgroundFetchInte- rval.
setMinimumBackgroundFetchInterval
That by default is never.
这个默认值是 never
So you might go to all this trouble to say yeah, I want to
但你可能遇到所有这些麻烦，我想要
do background fetching and all this stuff, and then if you
在后台获取数据，所有这些事情，然后如果你
don't call this method to set your fetching interval to
没有调用这个方法来设置你的获取间隔为
something besides never, you'll never get woken up.
某个值而非 never，你永远不会被唤醒
Usually you set it to minimum, this interval minimum,
通常你设置它为 minimum，这个间隔 minimum
which is like, wake me up as much as you can.
就是尽可能多的唤醒我
The system is kinda cool for this background fetching.
对于这个后台获取，系统是相当酷的
It kinda watches when the user uses your app, and
它检测到，当用户使用你的应用时，
the more the user uses your app,
越多用户使用你的应用
the more it's gonna let the background fetching happen,
它越有可能让后台获取发生
because it's gonna figure the more it use.
因为它需要计算它使用越多
It'll even kinda look at times of day.
它甚至一天检查几次
This person runs this app every morning at 9:00,
这个用户每天早上 9:30 运行这个应用
between 9:00 and 9:15, so
在 9:00 和 9:15 之间，因此
we're gonna let this background fetch run at 8:30.
我们需要让后台获取发生在 8:30
'Kay.
So it's pretty smart system for that.
对于这个，它是个非常聪明的系统
I told you could ask for more time when you get
我告诉过你们，当你在后台时你可以
backgrounded, you do that with this method
请求更多的时间，你通过这个方法
backgroundTaskWithExpirationH- andler.
backgroundTaskWithExpirationHanler 来实现
And so you get this background task.
因此你得到这个后台任务
You get to stay alive then until you call end
你可以保持运行，知道你调用
background task.
endBackgroundTask
If you don't call end background task pretty quickly
如果你在调用 backgroundTaskWithExpirationHandler
after you call backgroundTaskWithExpirationH-
后没有很快调用 endBackgroundTask
andler, it's going to say I give up on you, and kill you.
系统会表示我放弃你了，然后杀死你
And also the next time you ask for
然后下次你请求后台任务
a background task with expiration it's gonna say,
超时时，它将
no I don't give that guy ones, he doesn't end his.
不会给你时间，因为你没有结束这个
So you gotta really be sure you call end background task
所以你实际需要保证你调用 endBackgroundTask
when you do this other thing.
当你用这个做其他事情
There's a little spinner if you look at device well,
这里有个小的 spinner，如果你看设备
maybe we can see it in, I don't know, Safari maybe?
你可以在里面看到这个，我不知道，可能 Safari？
You see the little spinner up there?
你们看到上面的这个 spinner 了吗？
Right by the AT&T whatever,
在 AT&T 旁边
wireless thing there was a little spinner that spun.
无线的东西，这里有一个小的 spinner 在转动
That, you can control as well.
这个，你也可以控制
You can turn that on and
你可以打开或者关闭
off if your app accesses the network.
如果你的应用访问网络
Unfortunately, it's a boolean, so if you have multiple
不幸的，它是布尔值，因此如果在
places in your app that were accessing the network you have
你的应用中有许多地方访问网络，你需要
to figure out how to turn it on and off appropriately.
知道怎样正确关闭和打开这个
Yeah?
>> I don't think your phone is plugged in.
我不认为你的手机插进去了
>> Oh, sorry.
Yeah. Let's see here.
让我们看看这里
It's plugged in, it just disconnects every time it goes
它插进去了，只是每次它进入
into sleep mode here.
睡眠状态它就断开连接了
So, I don't know, let's search for something.
我不知道，让我们搜索一些东西
Okay, watch the status bar at the top there.
看看顶部的状态栏
You see how there's that little spinner spinning?
你们看这个小小的 spinner 如何旋转？
Okay?
You can turn that on and off.
你们可以打开和关闭这个
'Kay?
And yeah keep reminding me if I refer to this and
如果我提到这个而它没有在上面
it's not up there.
记得提醒我
You can also find out about things like,
你们也可以发现一些东西，比如
that preferred content size category notification,
preferredContentSizeCategory 通知
well you can also just ask UI application what that is
任何时候你都可以请求 UIApplication 给你
any time you want.
任何你想要的东西
And you can find out what state you're in,
你可以找出你处于哪个状态
are you in the foreground, or in the background,
你是在前台，还是在后台
are you active, inactive?
你是活跃的，还是不活跃的？
You can find all that out as well.
你可以知道所有这些
So U application has a lot of cool stuff in it as well.
因此 UIApplication 自己也有许多很酷的东西
So there's another interesting thing called Info.plist.
这里有另外一个有趣的东西叫做 Info.plist
Dot plist because it's a property list.
.plist，因为它是个属性列表
You remember a property list is any combination of
你们记得一个属性列表是字典、数组
dictionaries and arrays and strings and dates, in datas.
字符串、日期的任何组合
And Info.plist contains a lot of settings in your app.
Info.plist 包含很多你应用的设置
And you can actually click on it directly.
实际上你可以直接点击它
It's in that supporting files area and you'll see it.
它在这个 supporting files 区域，你可以看到
What you're seeing up here is the x code's property list
你在这里看到的东西是 Xcode 的属性列表
editor, which lets you edit an arbitrary property list as
编辑器，它让你编辑你看到的
you can see there.
任意属性列表
And it'll show you all the kinda setting,
你可以看到所有的设置
some of the settings of your app.
一些你应用的设置
You can even look at this in XML format.
你甚至可以以 XML 格式查看它
If you right click on it and
如果你右击这个，然后
switch to source code mode you can see it in XML.
切换到源代码模式，你可以以 XML 格式查看它
So this is that exact same property list in XML, raw XML.
因此这个是 XML 格式的完全一样的属性列表，裸 XML
But you usually edit the Info.plist things in
但通常地你在 Info.plist 中编辑属性
the project settings, which you get by clicking on
设置，你通过点击导航栏的左上角
the project in the upper left of the navigator.
的 project 来做设置
You see I've clicked on it there.
你们看已经点击了它
And then you can see there's General Settings.
你们可以看到这里是 General 设置
So, for example, things like what device orientations you
比如，比如你的应用支持的设备方向
support, portrait or portrait upside-down, or landscape left
垂直或者垂直上下，或者水平左
and right, which you can see there's a UI for there,
和右，这里是 UI
that's gonna set things in your Info.plist.
这会设置你的 Info.plist 里的东西
'Kay?
Now I'm gonna do a demo today and
今天我要开始做一个例子
in the demo I'm gonna add some stuff to make my application
在例子中，我将添加一些东西，让我的应用
know about a certain document type.
知道怎么打开某种类型的文档
I'm actually gonna do it by editing the Info.plist
实际上，我直接编辑 Info.plist 来实现
directly, because it's a lot faster and, you know,
这个，因为这会很快，你们知道的
we're gonna be time constrained here.
我们这里有时间限制
But you usually wouldn't do that.
但通常你们不这么做
Usually you would be clicking settings here in your project
通常，你们会点击你们项目的设置 UI
settings UI.
里的设置来实现
So the Info.plist you can kinda look through and
所以 Info.plist 你们可以看看
see what's in there.
它里面都有什么
A lot of that stuff's kind of arcane,
有许多东西比较晦涩难懂
you don't really even, hardly even know what it is.
你们甚至不知道它是什么
It's just for the application.
它只是为了应用
But there are some things in there that
但有些东西是
are pretty important, pretty obvious,
非常重要，非常明显的
like what document types do I recognize, things like that.
比如我认识的 document types，类似这类的
Okay, capabilities.
capabilities
So, some features in your app, quite a few actually,
你的应用的一些特征，实际上有很多
require enabling.
要求 enabling
In other words,
换句话说
you can't use them in your app until you enable them.
你在应用中不能使用它们直到你 enable 它们
Now, most of these are server features like iCloud or
它们大部分是服务特征比如 iCloud 或者
Game Center, or they're interoperability features,
Game Center，或他们是互用性特征
where you're gonna be inter-operating with other
你将和系统的其他部分做内部交互
parts of the system like the Passbook or things like that.
比如 Passbook 或者类似的东西
Okay?
So you turn these on in Project Settings under
所以你在 Project Settings 中的 Capabilities
Capabilities.
下把这些功能打开
You get this list right here.
你有这个列表
This is the current list as of the time I took the screen
这个是我几天前屏幕截图的
shot a few days ago.
列表
And you just switch those little switches,
你们可以改变这些 switches
the on off switches, on or off to enable this.
开关 switches，开或关来 enable 这个
Kind of a little bit of a warning about here is that
这里有一个小小的警告，
some of these things, the server based technologies
这些东西中的一些，基于服务的技术
require a normal developer program.
要求一个正常的开发者程序
The free University program that some of you are on,
你们中有些是免费的通用项目
doesn't really support that.
实际上并不支持这个
So if you wanted to do some of these things for
所以如果你们想在你们的期末项目中
your final project,
做这些设置
you might have to join the actual developer program.
你们可能需要加入实际的开发者项目
'Kay, so this is an FYI there.
这是 FYI
If you click on the little triangle to the left of any of
如果你们点击这些东西的左边的
these things, it'll actually give you
三角形，实际上它会给你一个
a little description of what the heck this thing is.
小小的描述，告诉你这个东西到底是什么玩意
'Kay?
So you can click on maybe In-App purchases and
你可以点击，也许是应用内购买
it'll tell you, oh, this is what enables you to, the user
它会告诉你，这个能够让你做什么，用户
to buy things to extend your app internally, etc.
在你应用内可以买东西
So I encourage you to look through all these things and
我建议你们浏览所有这些东西
see what's available.
看他们都能做什么
It kinda gives you a feeling for
这有点像给你一种感觉
how much stuff there is in iOS and how little we can really
在 iOS 中有许多东西，但在这门课程的
cover in just basically nine weeks of this course.
九周里我们只能涉及很少一部分
But, it's still kind of fun to look at what's in here.
但依然有趣，来看看这里有什么
Okay?
And these capabilities, sorry, question back there.
这些 capabilities，抱歉，有问题？
>> So for the app [INAUDIBLE] map to run your app,
对于你应用中的应用地图
would that be supported in this, or
它能否支持这个，或
do you have to do a different thing to create another map?
你需要创建另一个应用来做不一样的事情？
>> So you're talking about maps?
你在问地图？
So the question is, if I want to use a third party map
问题是，如果我使用第三方的地图
API or something, do I need to enable this or something?
API 或者其他的，我是否需要打开这个或者其他？
No. This is just enabling what
不，这只是使你的应用
your app can do, what it's capabilities are.
能够做一些事情，它的 capabilities 是什么
So for example if you're a map providing app, you would go
比如，如果你是个提供地图的应用，你就要在
here and enable your, you know, turn it on and all that.
这里打开功能，还有所有这些
You see what I'm saying?
你明白我所说的吗？
The end-user, they benefit from whatever capabilities
最终用户，他们从这些应用创建时注册的
these apps have signed up for when they were built.
任何 capabilities 中受益
Right? So this is a build setting
这是个 build 设置
essentially.
很重要
And it has a little bit to do with the coordination of your
这和你的 bundle identifier 的协调性有点相关
bundle identifier with what's going on at Apple servers and
在苹果服务器做了什么还有
all that stuff.
所有这些东西
So it's more than just turning it on, there's sometimes,
这不仅仅是打开它，有时候
there's some payload that has to be kind of arranged.
有些负荷需要被管理
All right?
So the demo I'm gonna do here is kinda setting us up for
所以这里我要做的例子，是为了周三
Wednesday.
创建的
I'm gonna show you how to do AirDrop to drop something into
我将给你演示如何使用 AirDrop 从 Mac
your app, 'kay, from the Mac.
拖一些东西到你们的应用，
Which is really kinda cool,
这非常酷
because you got this iPhone and let's say you wanna import
因为你们有这个 iPhone，让我们假设你想要导入
something, you know, an image or,
一些东西，你们知道的，一张图片或
you know, any kind of file, a pdf file even, whatever.
你们知道的，任何文件，pdf 文件，甚至任何其它的
You'd like to be able to just basically drag it, drag and
你们想要能够拖拽它，拖拽然后
drop it from your desktop.
从你的桌面上拖放
So the example I'm gonna do here is on Wednesday,
这里这个例子，我将在周三做
I'm gonna build an app that if you go on vacation, and,
我要创建一个应用，如果你们在度假
let's say, you take a bunch of photos that are,
你们拍了很多照片
have GPS tags on them, and maybe you even go hiking,
这些照片有 GPS 标签，甚至也许你们去滑雪
and you have a little GPS monitor,
你们有一个小的 GPS 显示器
or let the iPhone keep track of where you go, and
让 iPhone 追踪你的足迹
you wanna draw the track of where you hiked, or whatever.
你想要画出你滑雪的轨迹，或其它任何东西
Okay?
So we're gonna build an app on Wednesday that does both of
我们将在周三创建一个应用，能够做
those things.
这两种事情
Let's you take some information about photos and
你们获取了照片的一些信息
their location or a track and draw them on a map.
它们的地点或轨迹，然后在地图上画出
Okay?
Now to do that app,
现在开始做这个应用
we need to import that vacation information.
我们需要导入度假信息
Okay? I went on vacation,
我在度假中
I need the info.
我需要这个信息
And we're gonna do that with AirDrop and
我们通过 AirDrop 来实现
we're gonna to do it, air dropping GPX files.
我们要做这个，空中拖拽 GPX 文件
A GPX file is a file that just has a list of GPS coordinate
一个 GPX 文件是这样的文件，它有 GPS 坐标相关信息的列表
related information, like waypoints that you were at
比如你停下拍照的地点
where you maybe took a photo and
the track if you took a hike or whatever.
或你滑雪的轨迹，或任何其它的
So that's called a GPX file,
这叫做 GPX 文件
it's just kind of a public file format.
这只是一个公共文件格式
It's XML, but it's XML with a certain extension, GPX.
它是 XML，但是带了点扩展的 XML，GPX
And I'm gonna show you how you can make it, so you can just
我将演示你们可以做到的，你们可以
drag a GPX file into your iPhone app from your Mac.
从 Mac 电脑从拖一个 GPX 文件到你们的 iPhone 应用中
Okay?
So let's first talk about how that's gonna work here.
首先，让我说说这是如何工作的
So on the Mac, you just go here to AirDrop.
在 Mac 上，你只需要到这里 AirDrop
You've probably, how many people have used AirDrop for
你们可能，许多人已经使用过 AirDrop？
anything?
About only by half, okay.
只用了一半
Interesting.
很有趣
So AirDrop's really cool.
AirDrop 相当酷
So we got a lot of people here with various devices.
这里我们有许多人有不同的设备
And here, I'm gonna turn this guy on and you're
这里，我要把这个家伙打开，你们
gonna see that he shows up right here, CS192p iPhone6+.
将看到它在这里出现，CS192p iPhone6+
Can you see that?
你们可以看到吗？
And so if I have a file, like my Vacation.gpx right here,
如果我有一个文件，比如我的 Vacation.gpx
you see this is a GPX file.
你们可以看到这是个 GPX 文件
I can actually just drag and drop it onto here.
实际上我可以拖拽，然后拖到这上面去
Okay. To transfer it to my Mac or
把它从我们的 Mac 传输到
to my iPhone.
我的 iPhone上
But when I do that, sorry.
但当我做这个时，抱歉
Cancel.
取消
Its too bad this drops all the time,
一直这样拖放很糟糕
its a little bit annoying.
有点恼人
So, I'm gonna drag it again.
我再次拖放
Okay.
Drag it on here.
从这里拖放
So what happens right now is it says, oh,
现在发生了什么，它说
AirDrop someone wants to drag this GPX file to your Mac, but
AirDrop 有人想要拖这个 GPX 文件到你的 Mac 上，但
you have no app that can handle this.
你没有一个应用可以处理这个
So it's saying,
所以它表示
do you want to go to the App Store to get an app?
你想要到应用商店下载一个应用？
Which I don't want to go to the App Store,
但我不想到应用商店
I want to write my own app that handles GPX files.
我想要编写我自己的应用来处理这 GPX 文件
So that's what we're gonna do.
这就是我们将要做的
We're gonna write our own app here to handle GPX files.
这里我们要写我们自己的应用来处理这个 GPX 文件
All right. So let's go to Xcode.
好吧，我们打开 Xcode
So we're gonna create a new project here.
这里我们要创建一个新的项目
Now this project is going to show you how to do
这个项目要向你们演示如何处理
the AirDrop.
AirDrop
I'm also gonna show you how to do notifications.
我会向你们演示如何处理通知
Okay? Cuz that's an important thing
明白如何做也是很重要
to understand how to do as well.
的事情
So, I'm gonna call this app Tracks, because it keeps track
我称这个我为 Tracks 应用，因为你保持纪录
of where you go on your vacations or
你度假中的路径或
whatever with GPX file.
任何 GPX 文件
So we call we're gonna put it in the place we always put
我们要把它放在我们经常放
everything.
的地方
Okay.
Here it is, right here.
这就是了，这里
I am not going to move the AppDelegate out of the way
这次我不移动 AppDelegate
this time.
Okay? So the first time, yehey.
第一次，
We get to actually do something with
我们实际在我们的 AppDelegate
our AppDelegate, but
做些事情，但
I'm gonna move those things out of the way.
我要把这些东西移出
But we're gonna sneak in there and look at info.plist, so
但我们溜到这里，看看 info.plist
kind of get both of those things.
有这两者
All right.
So here's our ViewController.
这是我们的 ViewController
How do we want to do this?
我们要怎么处理这个？
Well, the most important thing we need to do to make our app
要让我们的应用可以处理 GPX 文件最重要的事情是
be air droppable for GPX is to register with our app that we
我们需要注册我们的应用
know what a GPX file is.
我们知道 GPX 文件是什么
Okay?
And we can do this in our project settings over here
我们可以在 Info 中做这个
in Info.
设置
You see down here at the bottom of Projects and
你们看项目的底部
Info is Document Types.
Info 是一个文档类型
So these are all the types of documents I know about.
这些是我知道的所有文档类型
And then also Imported UTIs.
你们也有导入的 UTIs
These are all the basically URL like descriptions of
它们基本上是类似文件描述的
a file.
URL
So I kind of need to do both of those things.
我要处理这两个
I need to describe what a GPX file is.
我需要描述 GPX 文件是什么
And then I just say, yes, that's a type I support.
我设置，这是我支持的文件类型
Now, I can do all this by clicking the plus sign
我点击这里的加号
here and here.
来做这个设置
But I want to show you another demo.
我想演示另一个例子
So, I'm gonna do this is kind of fast mode,
这个我要快一点演示
which I'm just gonna go to the Info.plist, because this
我打开 Info.plist，因为这个
information's going to be put in the Info.plist.
信息要放在 Info.plist
And I'm gonna edit it in source mode.
我要以源码形式编辑它
So I'm just going here and saying,
我在这里，
edit it as Source Code.
以源码形式编辑
Now you can see it's an XML file here.
你们可以看到这是个 XML 文件
And I actually prepped all of the stuff necessary here,
实际上，我布置了作业，所有这里需要的东西
which you can look through later at your leisure.
你们有空的时候可以浏览下
Wait, for GPX files, but you can see
等等，对于 GPX 文件，但你们可以看到
it's basically that I say that it's got file name extent,
它基本上，扩展了文件名
file extensions GPX, but that it is a XML file.
GPX 文件扩展，但它是一个 XML 文件
All right.
And then up here, I'm saying, the documents I support.
这上面，我支持的文档
I support this, which is my own private GPX type and
我支持这个，这是我自己的私人 GPX 类型
then that's linked to the type down here.
它关联到下面这个类型
So, I'm just gonna copy this and go over here.
我要拷贝这个，然后到上面这里
And actually,
实际上
just paste it right at the bottom of this down here.
在这下面底部粘贴
Paste.
粘贴
Okay.
So, I basically put that stuff in there.
我基本上把这个东西放到这里了
I can even go back to Property List mode and
我甚至可以回到属性列表模式
you can see that it added it here at the bottom.
你们可以看到，它在底部添加了这个
Okay.
So here's my types.
这是我的类型
And if I go back to my Project Settings,
如果我回到我的项目设置
I can see them here as well.
我也可以在这里看到
I can see now I have one document type,
我可以看到现在我有一个文档类型
it's a GPX file and I can import GPX.
它是一个 GPX 文件，我可以导入 GPX
So that's the key thing you need to do to make AirDrop
这是你让 AirDrop 工作需要做的关键的事情
work, it's just define the document type you
它定义了你愿意被拖放的
are willing to have dropped on you.
文档类型
Okay?
Now, once you've defined that, now the system,
一旦你定义了，现在系统
any time someone wants to open a GPX file,
任何时候有人想打开 GPX 文件
they're gonna ask me if I can do it in my app and
它们会询问我是否能在我的应用中处理这个
they do that here in the AppDelegate.
他们在 AppDlegate 中做这个事情
Now you can see the AppDelegate kind of gives you
现在你们可以看到 AppDelegate 给你
stubs for didFinishLaunchingWithOptions,
didFinishLaunchingWithOptions 的东西
ResignActive, EnterBackground, Foreground, even gives you
ResignActive，EnterBackground，Foreground，甚至给你
a little explanation of when you're supposed to use those.
一个什么时候你应该使用这些的小解释
We're not going to use any of those, so
我们不使用这里的任何东西
I'm gonna delete that.
我要删除这些
Okay?
So you can go look at that in any app that you build,
你可以在任何你创建的应用中看看这个
it's always going to put that, oops, those in there, so
它总是把这些放在这里
that you can find out about it.
你们可以找出它们
Don't ever delete this thing, though.
永远不要删除这个
[LAUGH] Var window.
Var window
The AppDelegate has a pointer to the window where all your
这个 AppDelegate 有个指针指向你的所有
UI is.
UI 所在的 window
And it needs to have that.
它需要有这个
It gets set when the storyboard gets loaded.
当 storyboard 加载时，这个 window 被设置
It is possible to reach into your UI here through this
通过这个访问你的 UI 是可能的
thing and start talking to your ViewControllers.
然后开始和你的 ViewControllers 通讯
I recommend against that.
我不建议这么做
Okay?
You do not want to be reaching down into there,
你不会想在这里做这些
because if you ever went into your storyboard and
因为如果你曾在你的 storyboard
changed whether something was in a split view or
改变任何在 split view 或
in navigation controller, now this code's going to break,
navigation controller 的任何东西，现在这些代码就被破坏了
it's not going to work.
它不会工作
And it also is not very object orientated in that MVCs should
这一点都不面向对象， MVC 应该
be their own thing and
做它们自己的事情
they should kind of work on their own.
它们应该只做它们自己的事情
They shouldn't need some outside intervention to be
它们不应该有外部打断
coming in and talking to them to make them work, okay?
进来然后告诉它们让它们工作
You want to think of MVCs as these objects,
这些对象你们要想想 MVC
essentially kind of meta objects,
元对象非常重要
even though they're made up swift objects inside.
即使他们在内部创建 swift 对象
But they have an API and they work on their own.
但它们有一个 API，它们自己可以工作
They're independent.
它们是独立的
They do what they do,
它们做自己可以做的
just like any other well designed object oriented API.
就像任何其他设计良好的面向对象 API
All right. So the method that we want to
我们在 AppDelegate 中要实现的方法
implement in our AppDelegate to open a URL is called
是打开一个 URL，叫做 application: handleOpenURL
application handle OpenURL, you see it right here.
这里你们可以看到
There's a lot of other things you can see.
你们可以看到很多东西
There's, look at all these things.
这里，看这所有东西
Many, many things we can do here.
我们可以在这里做很多事情
But we want handle open URL.
但我们想要 handleOpenURL
And all we need to do and handle OpenURL,
所有我需要做的事 handleOpenURL
we got this URL is go deal with it.
我们获得这个需要处理的 URL
So right now, I'm just going to print it out.
现在，我只是把它输出
So I'm gonna say, url equals url.
我要说， url 等于 url
Okay? Just so
we can see that our AirDrop is working.
我们可以看到我们的 AirDrop 工作了
And then you return true or false, whether you handled it.
然后你返回 true 或 false，你是否处理了它
So since all I'm going to do is print it out,
既然我要输出这个
I'm gonna say, true.
我要返回 true
Yes, I handled it.
是的，我处理了它
Okay?
So that's all I'm gonna do first here.
这是所有我首先要处理的
We're gonna run just that and then I'm gonna do another
我要运行这个，一会我需要处理一些
thing with notifications in a second here.
通知
So here's called tracks.
这个叫做 tracks
I'm running it on the device here, as you can see.
我在设备上运行这个，你们可以看到
Now the first time my app is installed where it is saying,
第一次我的应用安装了，它说
it can handle these new types, the system's going to
它可以处理这些新的类型，系统将会
recognize, oh, this guy handles GPX.
识别，这个家伙可以处理 GPX
Okay? So here's my app,
这就是我的应用
it didn't do anything, but it did register itself.
它没有做任何事情，但它注册了它自己
So now, I'm gonna go over here to my AirDrop again and
现在，我在这里，我的 AirDrop
going to, hope this guy shows up.
希望这个家伙会出现
So let's go back to our app here.
让我们回到我们的应用
We're gonna run our app.
我们要运行我们的应用
It's registered itself.
它注册了它自己
It says, oh yes, I handle GPX files.
他说，我可以处理 GPX 文件
So now, if I take a GPX file here, like this, and
现在，我放了一个 GPX 文件，比如这个
drag it on, okay, does the same thing, it transferred
然后拖放它，做同样的事情，它传输了
over, but notice the difference this time.
但注意这次的不同
Okay, this time it doesn't say get app, it says, do you
这次它没有说要下载一个应用，它说，你要在
accept it in tracks, because I'm running tracks right now.
tracks 中接受它？因为我现在正运行着 tracks
So I'll say, yeah, I accept it.
我说，是的，我接受它
And when I do, we're going to watch our console here
当我这么做时，我们要观察我们的 console
and its going to say at the bottom, its going to print out
它在底部，在文件被传输之后
the URL of the file after its been transferred.
它输出了这个文件的URL
So I hit accept and sure enough, right here, you see,
因此我点击接受，非常确定的，这里，你们看到
it's created this URL.
它输出了这个 URL
So it's put it in this place in my sandbox called documents
它把这个文件放在我的沙盒中，叫做
inbox vacation.gpx which we're going to talk about,
Documents/inbox/vacation.gpx，这个我们将要谈谈
the file system, a little later in this demo.
系统文件，一会在这个例子中
So, this file, GPX, was transferred over,
这个文件，GPX，被传输了
put on the local hard disk, flash drive of our phone,
放在本地的硬盘上，我们手机的闪存上
and made available to this app.
在这个应用中可用了
So now, I can open this URL up and do whatever I want.
现在，我可以打开这个 URL，做任何我想做的
So that's it, super simple to do AirDrop, it's just a matter
这就是了，AirDrop 超级简单，它只是
of registering those document types.
要注册这些文档类型的事情
But, in real world here now,
但在现实世界中
if I had dragged the GPX file on my document, I really need
如果我已经拖放了 GPX 文件，我实际需要
an NVC somewhere that can display this GPX file.
一个某处的 NVC 能够显示这个 GPX 文件
Okay?
Now, I guess I could go look at my window, and try and
我觉得我可以看看我的 window，尝试
look in a split view inside a navigation controller, and
在 navigation controller 中的 split view
find a view controller that can handle this GPX file, but
找一个视图控制器来处理这个 GPX 文件
that would be really, really bad.
但这非常非常糟糕
Really what I want to do is just have a radio station
实际上我需要的是有一个电台
that says, anybody who wants to find out when a GPX file
任何人想要知道什么时候一个 GPX 文件
has been loaded into this app, listen to this radio station.
已被加载到这个应用中，收听这个电台
And then we're going to send a message on the radio station
现在我们要在这个电台中发送一条消息
saying, up, one arrived.
有一个（文件）到达了
Okay, so that's how we're going to do this.
这就是我们如何处理这个
So let's start with the posting side,
让我们从发布消息开始
where we're going to post on the radio station.
这里我们将要在电台中发布
Now, when you have a radio station,
当你有一个电台时
you need to have a name for that radio station.
你需要给这个电台一个名字
I'm just going to create that as this kind of global struct.
我以全局结构体来创建这个
I'm going to call it static let.
我称这个为 static let
I'll call this GPXURL.
我叫它为 GPXURL
Actually, we'll call it notification.
实际上，我们称它为通知
So this is just a string which is the name of the radio
所以这只是这个电台名字的字符串
station, which we'll call the GPXURL Radio Station or
我们称之为 GPXURL 电台或者
something like that.
类似的东西
Okay?
And so, all I need to do to post on this radio station,
我所需要的是在这个电台中发布
whatever, is to get that center,
任何，它获取 center
the NS notification center, default center.
NSNotificationCenter.defaultCenter
So now I have the center, because I have to have
现在我有这个 center，因为我有这个
the notification center to either post or receive.
通知中心发送或接受消息
And then, I just need to create a notification,
然后，我只需要创建一个通知
which I do by saying NS notification.
我要说 NSNotification
And if you look at the creation of it,
如果你看这个通知的创建方法
you can create it with user info or not.
你可以带 userInfo 或不带来创建它
And I do want user info because,
我需要 userInfo，因为
when I send out on my radio station, I'm going to send
当我在我的电台发送消息时，我将在我的
the URL along as part of my user info, okay?
userInfo 中发送 URL
So I want this one, and
我需要这个
the name of it is GPXURL.notification.
它的名字是 GPXURL.notification
The object is myself, I'm the one sending on this station.
这个对象是我自己，我自己在这个电台发送消息
And user info is going to be.
userInfo 是
Well I need the key, GPXURL.key.
我需要这个键，GPXURL.key
We'll have to define that.
我们需要定义这个
And the value is this URL that was just passed through.
这个 URL 的值会被传递
There's no space here.
这里没有空间
Maybe we'll go to a larger font here.
也许我们需要更大的字体
How about this?
这样如何？
That better?
好一点了？
Okay.
So I need to define this key, so
我需要定义这个 key
I'll put that up here as well.
我也把它放在这上面
Static let the Key and this is just a key in that dictionary,
static let key，这只是这个字典中的一个键
that user info dictionary, so I'll call this GPXURL URL
这个 userInfo 字典，我称之为 GPXURL URL Key
key or something, I can call it whatever I want,
或其他的，我可以命名它为任何我想要的
it just has to be a unique key inside this user info thing.
你只需要在 userInfo 中有一个唯一的键
Okay, so, I've created the notification,
因此，我已经创建了这个通知
now I just tell the center post that notification.
现在我要告诉 center，发送这个通知
Okay, notification, and
通知，然后
that's going to broadcast on that radio station.
它会在电台中广播
So, anyone who's listening is going to find out when a URL
任何在收听的人都会发现一个 URL
gets dropped into this app.
已经被载入这个应用中
So now, how do we listen to the radio station?
现在，我们如何收听这个电台？
Well, who wants to listen?
谁想收听？
It's going to be this view controller over here.
这会是这里的视图控制器
So, I've got my storyboard right here and let's put
这里有我的 storyboard，让我们在
something in our storyboard like, how about a text view.
里面放一些东西，比如 text view
Where's the text view?
text view 在哪里？
Here it is. So I'm going to drag this text
这里，我将要把这个 text view
view in here, put this somewhere, maybe right there.
拖到这里，也许这里
Okay, let's make sure we do our constraints, sorry, set
让我们确保我们的 constraints，抱歉，设置
the constraints, let's take a look at these constraints.
constraints，让我看看这里的 constraints
Actually, I'm going to have the top space be
实际上，我想要顶部的空间为
the standard value away.
标准值
Okay?
So I've got this text.
我有了这个 text view
Let's get that out of there.
我们把这个拿出来
I've got this nice text field.
我有这个很好的 text field
Let's go ahead and create an outlet for
让我们继续，创建一个 outlet
that into our view controllers, control drag.
到我们的视图控制器，control 拖拽
I'll call that textview, okay?
我命名这个 textview
We don't need any of this.
我不需要这些
Okay?
So, that's that.
这就是了
So, we've got our text view outlet right here.
这里我们有我们的 textview outlet
Now, all I'm going to do is when that radio station
现在我们要做的是，当电台发送广播时
broadcasts, I'm going to put the URL into that text view.
我要把这个 URL 放到这个 textview 中
Okay now, on Wednesday, we'll do much more.
现在，周三，我们会做更多
We'll put a map and we'll draw all this stuff, but here,
我们会放一个地图，我们将在这里把所有东西都画出
that's all I'm going to do.
这是我所有要做到
So, I'm going to put this in viewDidLoad,
我要把这个放在 viewDidLoad
super.viewDidLoad.
super.viewDidLoad
Don't forget, by the way,
不要忘记，顺便提下
in your view controller life cycle methods,
在你们的视图控制器的生命周期方法中
you need to call super.
你需要调用 super
I noticed a few of you not doing that.
我注意到你们中有些人没有这么做
So, to make this work, I'm just going to get my center,
为了让这个工作，我只是获取我的 center
NSNotificationCenter, default center.
NSNotificationCenter.defaultCenter
[SOUND] Default center.
DefaultCenter
Okay, I've got the center.
我获取了这个 center
You remember that I need a cue to put it on.
你们记得我需要一个线程来放置这个
So I'm going to do it on the main cue.
我要在主线程中做这个
So, I'm going to do NSOperationQueue.mainQueue.
我要处理 NSOperationQueue.mainQueue
And, I'm looking for this URL broadcast
我从 appDelegate 寻找 URL 广播
from the app delegate, which I can get by saying
通过 UIApplication.sharedApplication().delegate 来
UIApplication.sharedApplicati- on().delegate, because the app
获取代理，因为 AppDelegate 只是一个
delegate is just the delegate of UI applications.
UIApplication 的代理
So, now I have all the information I need to do this.
现在我有需要的所有信息
I'll make this even wider.
我要把这个变宽一些
And I'm just going to center, add observer for name.
我要在 center，addObserverForName
So here's the add observer for the name, right here.
这是 addObserverForName， 这里
Just the one we want, the one that has a block at the end.
这就是我们想要的，这个在结尾有一个 block
The one we want is GPXURL.Notification.
我们要的是 GPXURL.Notification
We're interested when the app delegate sends it.
我们感兴趣的是 appDelegate 发送这个通知
We want the queue to be that main queue.
我们想要的队列是主队列
And we're going to use our nice swift thing
我们要使用我们好用的 swift 的东西
where we can put a closure after a method like this.
这里，我们可以像这样在一个方法后放一个闭包
Okay?
Here's the notification, right?
这是 notification
So we'll just say notification,
所以我们就写 notification
actually don't even need to put this
实际上我们甚至不需要把这个
void business in there.
空的东西放在这里
So there's the notification.
这是 notification
So inside here, this is going to be called every time that
在这里面，每次电台发送广播时
radio station broadcasts,
这个都会被调用
in other words every time a URL is dropped in.
换句话说，每次一个 URL 被放入时
And so, all I"m going to do here is I'm going to say,
这里我所要做的是，我要说
if let the URL equal the notification?.userInfo and
if let url = notification?.userInfo，然后
we'll look up in there the GPXURL.key, and
我们在这里检查 GPXURL.Key，然后
notice I had to put some question marks in there
注意这里我写了几个问号
because some of these are optionals.
因为他们中的一些是 optionals（类型）
Okay, this is probably not actually an optional.
这个很可能不是 optional
But, and then, that is an NSURL because, remember,
但，然后，这是一个 NSURL，因为记住
that this user info dictionary, the values are any
这个 userInfo 字典，它的值是任何
object, so I have to cast it to what I actually want.
对象，所以我需要把它转换成我实际需要的
And now, I'm just going to say
现在，我让
self.textView.text equals Received this URL.
self.textView.text = "Receive \(url)"
Okay?
Any questions about that?
这里有问题吗？
So now, when I run this Trax,.
现在，当我运行这个 Trax
Instead of it putting it on the console,
不是把它（URL）输出在 console，而是
it's gonna actually put it in the content,
输出在 content 上
that text view of track.
track 的 textView 上
So let's go over here again.
让我们再到这里
Luckily this time it's showing.
幸运地，这次它出现了
There we go.
开始了
So let's go over here.
让我们到这里
I'm just going to drag it on here.
我要把它拖放到这里
Okay, it's asking me if I want to accept it again.
它又问我是否要接受它
I'm gonna say Accept.
我接受了
And there it is.
这就是了
It puts it on there.
它把它（URL）输出在这里了
Okay, now interesting see it says it's Vacation-1.gpx
看，有趣的是，这次它输出 Vacation-1.gpx
this time, where it was just vacation before.
之前它只是 vacation
And if I drag it on again, it's gonna be Vacation-2.
如果我再次拖放，它将会是 Vacation-2
Okay, so it's collecting these things.
所以它在收集这些东西
See Vacation-2?
看，Vacation－2？
So now I actually have three of these things that
实际上，现在我有三个这样的文件
I've dragged in three times.
我拖放三次了
Okay?
So you can see now how this ViewController right here
现在你们可以看到这里的 ViewController
in an object-oriented way is very self-contained.
以一种面向对象的方式，非常独立的
It displays GPX files somehow, and all it does is sign up to
它以某种方式显示 GPX 文件，它所做的是注册
the radio station that says I received one.
电台，它在收听这个文件
And then it goes and does what it does.
然后它走了，做它该做的
And again on Wednesday we'll actually draw the map.
周三，我们会绘制这个地图
Okay?
Any question about that?
这里有问题吗？
All righty, that is it.
好吧，这就是了
Back to our slides.
回到我们的幻灯片
Where's my slides here?
我的幻灯片在哪里，这里？
Slides, okay, all right.
幻灯片，好的
So the next thing we'll talk about is core motion.
接下来我们要谈论的是 core motion
So core motion is what's happening with the hardware.
core motion 是硬件在做什么
And the primary inputs to that are the accelerometer,
最主要的输入是，加速计
the gyro, and the magnetometer.
陀螺仪，磁力计
Not all devices have all those things.
不是所有的设备都有这三样东西
Newer devices have them all.
新的设备都有这三个
But older devices, some of them don't have it.
但老设备，有一些是没有这些的
The class that you use to get all the information about this
你们使用的获取这些信息的类
is called CMMotionManager, so CM is core motion.
叫做 CMMotionManager，所以 CM 是 core motion
That's the name of the framework this is all in.
这是这个框架的名字，所有东西都在这里面
And so the motion manager, you really only want to have
所以 motion manager，在每个应用中你实际
one of these per app, because you only have one gyro, okay,
只需要它们中的一个，因为你只有一个陀螺仪
and one accelerometer, one magnetometer.
一个加速计，一个磁力计
So you really want one of these.
所以你实际要它们中的一个
So you want to put it in some global space and share it,
如果你想要把它放在一些全局空间并分享它
like maybe your app delegate would be a good place.
也许你的 appDelegate 是一个好的地方
The way you use the motion manager,
你使用 motion manager 的方式
there's really two ways to do it.
实际上有两种方式使用它
Polling, which is, you create one of these motion managers.
Polling，这个是，你创建这些 motion manager 中的一个
You check to see what hardware is available like,
你检查哪个硬件可以使用
is accelerometer available, gyro, or whatever.
比如加速计可用，还是陀螺仪，还是其他任何的
And then you just start asking for the value over and over.
然后你开始不停的询问这个值
Usually, we don't do it that way.
一般的，我们不这么用
We do it the second way,
我们使用第二种方式
which is, we check to see what's available.
也就是，我们检查哪个可用
And then if it's available, we say how often we want to
然后如果它可用，我们会说我们想要多久
receive an update, 'kay, how often we want to get
收到一个更新，比如我们想要加速计
the acceleration from the accelerometer for example.
加速多频繁
And then you register a closure, 'kay,
然后，你注册一个闭包
a block of code, that will get called each time.
一个代码块，它每次都会被调用
'Kay, so that's a much more sensible way to do this than
这种方式要比 polling 来得明智些
polling, and so that's the way we're going to do this.
这就是我们要使用的方式
Notice that I had mentioned checking
注意，我提到了检查它的
the availability of it.
可用性
Well, because some devices don't have a gyro, for
因为有些设备并没有一个陀螺仪
example, you have to check.
你必须检查
And you do that by just asking the motion manager,
你只需要询问 motion manager
accelerometer Available?
加速计是否可用？
And that will return true if it's available and
然后如果可用它会返回真
false if it's not.
否则返回假
Okay, you can do that for all the different hardware things.
所有不同的硬件你都可以使用这种方式
Then you start the motion manager reporting to you.
然后 motion manager 开始向你发送报告
Now, again, if you're polling, you can just say start update.
再次，如果你使用 polling，你只需要开始更新
And then it will start updating it, and
然后它就会开始更新它
you can ask for the value at any time.
你可以在任何时候请求值
Okay? But we don't usually do
但通常我们不
it that way.
这么做
We'll talk about that in a second.
一会我们会谈到
And you can also find out whether the device is
你也可以检查当前设备是否在
actually looking at the accelerometer right now,
查看加速计
if anybody's interested in it, by saying accelerometer
如果有人对它感兴趣，也就是说加速计当前是
Active, or gyro Active, deviceMotion Active.
活跃的，或者陀螺仪或 deviceMotion 是活跃的
We'll talk about deviceMotion in a second, what that is.
一会我们谈谈 deviceMotion 是什么
And you can stop it also, and
你也可以停止它
it's very important to stop it because this thing
停止它是非常重要的，因为这东西
uses a lot of battery, okay, so you do not want this
消耗很多电量，你并不想用它
happening unless you're actually using the data.
除非你真的需要这个数据
That is very important to understand,
理解这点非常重要
and that's true of the GPS location stuff as well,
GPS 定位也是一样的
which we're gonna talk about on Wednesday.
我们周三来讲这个
You really want to turn this stuff off if
实际上你需要关闭这个，如果你
you're not using it.
没使用它
You do that with just saying, stop whatever Updates.
要关闭它，你只要停止任何更新
Okay? And that's true whether you're
不管你是使用 polling 或
polling or whether you're using the block-based one.
block-based 方式，都是可行的
All right, so let's look at the data structures here.
让我们看看这里的数据结构
They're very, very simple.
它们非常，非常简单
So, when you get acceleration data, it comes as x, y,
当你收集数据时，它们会是在 g 中的 x，y，z
z in g, g meaning acceleration due to gravity.
g 代表重力加速度
All right?
So If I have this phone sitting flat right here,
如果我让这个手机平躺在这里
it's going to be having the z-axis this way so it can tell
那么 z 轴会是这样，它会告诉你这样
you this way and then y is this way and x is this way.
y 是这样，x 是这样
So if you were to move it this way you'd get a lot of x
如果你以这种方式移动它，你会得到很多的 x
acceleration and deceleration.
加速和减速
If you move it this way you're gonna get a lot of z
如果你这样移动，你会得到很多的 z
acceleration, deceleration.
加速，减速
And if you just get the acceleration data directly,
如果你只是直接获取加速度数据
it includes the acceleration due to gravity.
它包含由于重力引起的加速度
So this phone right here, z is going to be 1.0 right now.
所以这里的这个手机，现在 z 会是1.0
'Kay?
If I turn it this way now, x is gonna be 1.0.
如果我把它变成这样，x 会是 1.0
'Kay?
Cuz it's got acceleration due to gravity.
因为它获取了重力加速度
Now if you have a gyro, you can get the acceleration
如果你有一个陀螺仪，没有重力你可以获取
without gravity, and we'll talk about that in a second.
加速度，一会我谈这个
If you get the gyro information,
如果你获取陀螺仪信息
then it's going to tell you about rotation rate.
它会告诉你转速
And it's going to tell you how fast the device
它会告诉你设备在 x，y，z 方向的
is rotating in the x, y, or z directions.
转速有多快
Okay, that's what a gyro tells you, is the rate of rotation.
这是陀螺仪会告诉你的，转速
The magnetometer is going to tell you
磁力计会告诉你
basically the magnetic field,
磁场
around your device, in each of the directions.
在你设备周围，每个方向上的
Okay.
That's what a magnetometer does.
这是磁力计所做的
It tells you magnetic field.
它告诉你磁场
That's how you can detect where true north is,
这是你怎么辨别真北在哪个方位上
for example.
举个例子
Now there's a very interesting one which is
现在有一个非常有趣的，就是
CMDeviceMotion, okay?
CMDeviceMotion
So it's another thing like accelerometer, gyro, or
这是和加速计，陀螺仪或
magnetometer.
磁力计相同的另一个东西
But the CMDeviceMotion is actually a combination
CMDeviceMotion 实际上是这三者的
of those things.
结合
So for CMDeviceMotion, if you ask for
对于 CMDeviceMotion，如果你请求
CMDeviceMotion updates, when you get to gravity,
CMDeviceMotion 更新，当你取得重力时
it's going to give you gravity.
它会给你重力
It's going to give you the user acceleration
没有重力它则给你用户加速度
without gravity.
In other words, it will separate gravity out, so
换句话说，它将区分重力
you can find out where gravity is, where that's pointing.
所以你能找到重力在哪里，它指向哪里
Right? Where is gravity pointing and
重力指向哪里
where is the user accelerating, separated?
用户在哪里加速，两者分开
And it can do that because it has the gyro.
它能这么做是因为它有陀螺仪
Right? So
it know what's happening this way, so it can tell you
它知道这种方式下会发生什么，它能告诉你
what's acceleration and what's rotation.
加速度是什么，什么在旋转
Okay? And similarly, for
类似地，对于
the rotation,
转向
it can give you unbiased data about the rotation.
它能给你转向有关的客观数据
Okay? Because it knows fixed points.
因为它知道固定的点
Maybe the magnetometer, for example,
比如，可能是磁力计
can tell us fixed points.
能告诉我们固定的点
And, so now you can get the attitude of your device
现在你能获取你的设备
with roll, pitch, and yaw.
滚动，投掷，偏航方向
You all know what that is?
你们都知道这是什么吗？
It's, kind of, an airplane thing.
它是类似于飞行
Right, so roll is how much you're rolling the device,
滚动是指你如何滚动你的设备
pitch is how much you're pitching it up and
投掷是你将它放的多上和多
down, right?
下
And then, yaw is,
然后，偏航是
kinda, how much you're rotating this direction.
类似，你如何转动这个设备
So it can give you that pure information unbiased if it has
它能给你客观的纯粹信息，如果你同时有
both the accelerometer, so it knows where down is, for
加速计，通过这个它知道下方在哪里，
example, or magnetometer.
或磁力计
And gyro has them all, can combine them.
磁力计拥有这全部，能够组合它们
So CMDeviceMotion is a really powerful mechanism to
CMDeviceMotion 真的是一种获取实际数据的
kinda get real data.
强大的机制
And same thing with magnetic field, okay?
磁场也是一样的
So how do you do this with not polling?
没有 polling 你怎么处理这个？
You do this registering a block.
你们注册一个 block 来实现
You just say, for example, for accelerometer,
你们可以，比如，对于加速计
startAccelerometerUpdatesToQu- eue.
startAccelerometerUpdatesToQueue
You give it queue, like the main queue, for
你可以给它队列，像主队列，比如
example, where you want this block to execute.
你想让这个代码块在哪里执行
And then you give it the handler, and the handler just
然后你给它 handler，这个 handler 需要一个
takes an argument which is the data, the accelerometer data,
数据参数，也就是加速度数据
and an error, if it got some sort of error.
还有一个 error，如果它获取了某些错误
And you can get errors.
你们可以得到错误
And similar for the gyro, similar for the DeviceMotion.
陀螺仪也是一样的，还有 DeviceMotion
And some of the errors you can get are things like
你能获取的一些错误是，比如
this activity is not authorized.
这个活动没有被授权
Because the user can actually go into their settings on your
因为用户实际上可以去设备的设置里
device and say I don't want this app to
我不想让这个应用从我这
get motion information from me.
获取设备运动信息
Okay, and other errors there, like requires movement.
其他的错误，比如要求移动
Obviously if you're asking for device motion and
显然，如果你请求设备运动
the device is sitting on the tabletop, it's not moving.
然而设备躺在桌面上，它没有移动
It can't give you any information.
它不能给你任何信息
You set the rate at which this closure is gonna be
你要设置这个闭包将被调用的频率
called by set accelerometerUpdateInterval to
可以通过设置 accelerometerUpdateInterval 为
whatever you want or deviceMotionUpdateInterval to
任何你想要的值，或 deviceMotionUpdateInterval
whatever you want as you might expect.
为任何你想要的值，你所期待的
It's in seconds, all right?
单位是秒
So, you don't wanna set this to high a rate.
你并不想设置这个为高频
Like if you set this higher then,
如果你设置的过高
maybe 30 to 60 hertz, it really can't
可能30到60赫兹，它实际上不能
barely even give you that information that fast.
这么频繁的向你提供信息
And you're gonna be calling your block a lot more and
你想要大量调用你的代码块
you're gonna be using a lot of power.
你将会使用很多电量
And so you really want to be careful to kinda do this at
所以这样做你要非常小心
a rate that gives you smooth response for whatever you're,
以一个它能给你任何你想要的及时响应的频率
however you're reacting, but not overly.
然而你会反应，但不过度
In fact, you might get a smoother response if you
实际上，如果你降低这个值
slow it down a little.
也许你会得到一个更顺畅的体验
'Kay?
Cuz if try to update too much,
因为如果更新太频繁
it might be a little too choppy.
可能有一些波动
So be careful with that update interval.
所以对于这个更新间隔要小心点
You can call that start gyro update with this handler
你可以多次调用这个，开始更新陀螺仪
multiple times and have multiple blocks going on, and
然后有许多 block 在进行中
that's perfectly legal.
这非常合理
'Kay? Even though you only have one
即使你只有一个陀螺仪
gyro, the motion manager can still call multiple different
只要你想，MotionManager 仍然可以有许多不同
blocks if you want.
block
Okay, or accelerometer.
或者加速计
Any time I use an example, gyro, accelerometer,
任何时候我使用一个，陀螺仪，加速计
magnetometer, device motion, they're all exactly the same.
磁力计，deviceMotion，它们完全一样
Okay, so, the demo I have for this is called Bouncer,
关于这个的例子叫做 Bouncer
and what we're going to do is we are going to do a dynamic
我们将要做的是，一个动画
animation, but we're gonna use real gravity, as the gravity.
但我们要使用真的重力，重力
'Kay, we're gonna hook up a gravity behavior to
我们要把一个重力行为挂钩到
actual real gravity.
现实中真的重力
'Kay?
So how do we do that?
我们要怎么做呢？
[SOUND] We're not actually gonna hook it up to real
我们实际并不是把它和
gravity.
真的重力挂钩
We're gonna hook it up to real device acceleration.
我们要把它和真的设备加速度挂钩
So the user can kinda move it around and
用户可以这样移动设备
also will be using gravity as well.
也会使用重力
So as I move my device around,
所以当我移动我的设备
I'm going to be having my dynamic animator affected by
我将让我的动画被
whatever acceleration the device is going through.
设备的任何加速影响
All right.
So let's go here to Bouncer.
让我们创建 Bouncer
It's a new project again, it's iOS apps,
一个新的项目，这是 iOS 应用
single view, Bouncer.
singleView，Bouncer
Okay, and put it in the place that we always do.
把它放在我们经常放的地方
Now, one thing I'm gonna do for
关于 Bouncer 我要做的一件事情是
Bouncer to make it a little easier on myself,
让他简单些
is I'm gonna make Bouncer not work in landscape mode.
我不让 Bouncer 在水平模式可用
I'm sure you'd like to do this for
我确信你们在作业中也会这样做
your homework assignment, as well.
But we are just going to make a portrait only.
我们只是做一个垂直模式的
Just to make the code a little simpler, cuz it's a demo.
让代码简单点，因为这是个例子
But we usually wouldn't do that in an app,
但在一个应用中我们通常不这么做
making it not work in landscape.
水平模式不能工作
Users kinda don't like that very much.
用户不会喜欢这样的
Okay. So,
I'm going to start right off the bat
我们开始
by creating a dynamic behavior, okay?
创建一个动画
Just like we did in the last one.
就像我们上次做的那样
So it's gonna be UiDynamicBahavior.
这会是 UiDynamicBahavior
I'm gonna call it BouncerBehavior, 'kay?
我称之为 BouncerBehavior
Cause I wanna capsulate all the behavior of the bouncer
因为我想要在一个类中封装 bouncer 的所有行为
into one class just like we did in Drop It, okay?
就像我们在 DropIt 中做的
So here our BouncerBehavior.
这是我们的 BouncerBehavior
I'm going to cheat and go over to DropIt.
我们要作弊下，在 DropIt
And steal a lot of the code out of there, so
从那里偷一些代码
let's go over to DropItBehavior.
让我们找到 DropItBehavior
Here's DropItBehavior, so I'm gonna actually copy the whole
这是 DropItBehavior，我要拷贝着全部
thing and paste it over here.
代码，粘贴到这里
[SOUND] 'Kay?
Now the differences between drop it and
dropIt 和 我的 BouncerBehavior
my bouncing behavior are kinda twofold.
不同处是双重的
Well, really, one major difference again is
实际上，一个主要的区别是
the gravity is gonna be driven by real gravity.
gravity 是被现实重力驱动的
But also I want the elasticity to be a little bit higher.
但我也想让 elasticity 大一些
Also, as some of you have noticed, you really want
你们有些已经注意到了，你真的想关掉
the friction to be off, and the resistance to be off.
friction，还有 resistance
Okay, you probably want that true for your breakout as
很可能你也想让你的突破是真的
well, cuz you want the thing to bounce around and
因为你想让这个东西反弹
flow naturally.
并自然跳动
So we do that.
所有我们做这个
The other thing, too,
另一件事情
is I don't really wanna call these things drops,
我不想叫这些东西 drop
because bouncer, they're not really dropping.
因为 bouncer，它们实际上并不下落
They're kinda bouncing around.
它们弹跳着的
They're just little blocks that are bouncing around.
它们是弹跳的小方块
So I'm gonna change those things.
我要修改这些东西
I'm gonna do Find and Replace in project here.
我要在项目中查找和替换
And hopefully you've found this little gem.
希望你已经发现这个小宝石
And I'm gonna replace drop with block.
我要替换 drop 为 block
So I wanna call these things blocks instead of drops.
我要称这些东西为 blocks 而不是 drops
So I'm just gonna Replace All.
我要替换全部
We don't wanna do snapshots.
我不想做快照
I'll do it for both cases.
两种情况我都要替换
Upper and lower case, Replace All.
大小写，替换全部
So now I have this block,
现在我有这个 block
this bouncer behavior that works on blocks.
这个 BouncerBehavior 在 block 工作
You see addBlock, removeBlock.
你们看到 addBlock，removeBlock
But otherwise, pretty much the same.
除此之外，几乎是相同的
'Kay. I'm just gonna tie its gravity
我要把它的重力和
to the accelerometer.
加速计绑定起来
Okay?
Everyone cool with where I am so far?
每个人都理解这些了吗？
So let's go to, and I'm just gonna do this all
让我们，我要在这个视图控制器中
in this view controller right here.
做所有这些
I'm not gonna create a game view or
我不想创建一个游戏视图或
do all those things because we only have ten minutes left.
做所有这些东西，因为我们只剩10分钟了
Wanna be able to do this whole demo.
想要让这个例子可用
So I'm just going to put it all in the top level view of
我要把它们都放在我的视图控制器的
my view controller,
最顶层
which you would never do, you don't usually wanna draw
这是你们永不会做的，你们通常不在你们的
directly in the top level view of your view controller.
视图控制器的顶层绘制这些
The top level view of your view controller is for
你们视图控制器的顶层是给
subviews, okay, you put subviews in there.
子视图的，你们在那里放子视图
But I'm gonna draw straight in there,
但我要直接在这里绘制
my bouncing ball, just for expediency sake.
我的弹跳球，仅仅是权宜之计
So I need a bouncer, which is my bouncer behavior, 'kay, so
如果我需要一个 bouncer，也就是我的 bouncerBehavior
that's just one of those things I just created,
这是我刚刚创建的其中一个东西
all right, that has the gravity and
它有重力
collision behaviors and
collisionBehaviors 和
all that stuff that I stole from drop it.
我从 dropIt 中偷来的所有东西
And of course, I need an animator.
当然，我需要一个 animator
So I'm gonna create a UIDynamicAnimator.
我要创建一个 UIDynamicAnimator
And do the same thing I did before which
和之前做的一样，
is UIDynamicAnimator, referenceView.
是 UIDynamicAnimator，referenceView
Self.view.
Okay? Instead of game view into
不是在 self.view 中的
self.view.
gameView
So I'm creating that lazy as we did before, so
我以 lazy 方式创建这个，和之前做的一样
I need to make this closure be executed to do this, okay?
为了这样我需要这个闭包被执行
It's the same as drop it.
这和 dropIt 一样
Oops, this is, must be colon.
这个，必须是冒号
All right?
So now I've got my bouncer and animator, so
现在我有我的 bouncer 和 animator
I'm just going to in viewDidLoad.
我要在 viewDidLoad 中
I'm just gonna say animator, addBehavior, the bouncer.
我输入 animator.addBehavior(bouncer)
'Kay? So now I've got this going.
现在我有这个东西
Course, super.viewDidLoad, I just talked about that,
当然，super.viewDidLoad，我刚才说过的
so don't wanna do that.
不要这么做
All right?
So there we go.
现在我们开始
So now we've got an animator.
我们有一个 animator
Anything we add now to the bouncer is going to start
现在我们在 bouncer 中添加的任何东西都会被
being affected by the bouncer behavior.
bouncerBehavior 所影响
If you, which we mostly stole from DropIt.
如果你们，我们从 DropIt 偷的大部分代码
All right, so how many?
多少呢？
Well, I'm gonna just add a block,
现在我只要添加一个方块
a little red block to my view which
一个小的红色方块到我的视图中
I'm gonna then be controlling with the accelerometer.
这个视图和加速计控制
So let's have a little function here called addBlock.
让我们写一个小的函数叫做 addBlock
It's going to return a UIView.
它返回一个 UIView
Okay, there's a block that I'm gonna add here, so
这是我要在这里添加的 block
let's create a new UIView, and its frame.
让我们创建一个新的 UIView，还有它的 frame
Let's start out.
让我们开始
Let's do CGRect.
让我们做 CGRect
We'll have its origin be CGPoint.zeroPoint,
我们有它的原点 CGPoint.zeroPoint
then I'll move it in the second to the right place.
一会我要把它移动到正确的地方
And we probably want a constant here for
这里我们可能需要一个方块
the block size.
大小的常量
So let's put a constant here, struct Constants.
这里我们放一个常量，结构常量
I really take the extra time to do this constants thing
我真的需要额外的时间来处理这个 constants
because you really don't wanna have magic numbers spread
因为我们不想让魔术数字在你们的
all out through all your code, okay?
代码中到处泛滥
You really wanna have your constants put into structs or
你真的需要把你的常量放在结构体或
grouped, or name space or something to get them so
组，或名字空间或管理它们的东西
that they're not scattered about your code.
这样它们不会分散在你们的代码中
Otherwise, people won't know what's really going on.
否则，人们不知道发生了什么
So, I'm gonna let BlockSize equal CGSize.
我要让 BlockSize 等于 CGSize
We'll just have block be 40 by 40.
我们有一个 40*40 的方块
That's a good starting size.
这是一个好的初始大小
We can see if we don't like it later.
我可以看一会我们是否喜欢它
So now, let's move the block to where we want, and
现在，让我们把方块移动到我们想要它的地方
I'm gonna start the block out
我想要在视图的中心
right in the center of the view.
开始这个方块
So that's just CGPoint, and, we'll say,
这个是 CGPoint，我们
view.bounds.midX and view.bounds.midY.
view.bounds.midX 和 view.bounds.midY
Again, notice that I'm using the bounds, not the frame.
再次，注意我正在使用 bounds，不是 frame
The frame would be my views,
frame 会是我的视图
super view which like the window or something.
父视图比如 window 或者其它
So I'd only use frame there.
这里我只使用 frame
Then we'll add that SubView(block), and
然后我们要添加这个 subView（block）
we'll return the block.
我们将返回 block
Okay, so now I have a way of basically
现在我们已经基本上添加方块
adding a block to the center of my view, okay?
到我的视图中心
So now that I have that, let's go ahead and add the block.
现在我有这个，让我们继续，添加方块
And I'm gonna do that,
我要做这个
I'm gonna add that block in my viewDidAppear.
我要在我的 viewDidAppear 添加这个方块
So as soon as my view appears if the block has not
一旦我的视图出现了，如果方块还没被加入
been added, I'm gonna add it.
我将添加它
Okay, and that's a common thing,
这是常有的事
again, to wait until view did appear to do something,
再次，等到视图出现再做一些事情
because you don't want to waste your time doing it until
因为你不想浪费时间，知道
it's actually gonna be on screen.
它真的在屏幕上出现了
So in view did appear, here.
在 viewDidAppear，这里
I'm gonna call super dot view did appear.
我要调用 super.viewDidAppear
And I need a little variable for my block.
我需要给我的 block 加一个小的变量
I'm going to make it be red, so
我要让它为红色
I'm going to call it red block.
我要称它为 redBlock
UIView, okay it's an optional, it starts out nil.
UIView，它是可选类型，开始它为 nil
And if my red block has not set yet, so if it equals nil.
我的 redBlock 还没被赋值，所以如果它等于 nil
Let em create my red block just by
让我们创建我的 redBlock
saying red block equals ab block,
让 redBlock 等于 addBlock
which is that function I just called, so now I created it.
就是我刚才调用的函数，现在我创建它了
We're gonna make my red block be red by Just setting it to
我们要让我的 redBlock 为红色的，让它的
background color equal to UI color red color.
backgroundColor 等于 UIColor.redColor()
So I created this red block.
我创建了这个 redBlock
I'm gonna add Red Block to the bouncer.
我要添加 redBlock 到 bouncer
And it should start bouncing.
它应该开始弹跳
So let's go take a look.
让我们看下
This is all we really need to do.
这是我们要做的全部了
We need to, exclamation point there, okay?
这里需要感叹号
So, that should be all that is necessary to make this thing
这是让这个发生的全部需要做的事情
happen, so let's go ahead and run this, all right?
让我们继续，运行这个，对吧？
Just in time, there's Bouncer.
很及时，这是 Bouncer
And sure enough, bouncer is bouncing.
非常确定，bouncer 在弹跳
Okay, now, it's bouncing exactly like drop it,
现在，它弹跳得完全像丢下它一样
because I stole drop it's behavior out of drop it,
因为我偷了 DropIt 中的丢下它的 behavior 代码
and so it's just like that.
所以这就像扔掉它一样
Now, if I move the phone, I pick the phone up here, and
如果我移动手机，这里我拿起手机
I'm moving it around, nothing happens.
我四处移动它，什么也没有发生
It doesn't do anything, right,
它什么也没做
because gravity is just set to be down at the bottom of
因为重力被设置为屏幕底部向下
the screen which is the default for gravity behavior.
这是默认的重力行为
So what we want to do here is link the acceleration of
我们需要的是，把设备的加速度，加速计
the device, the accelerometer to the gravity, okay?
和重力关联
So that when I tilt it this way,
这样当我这样倾斜它
this thing will slide down that way.
这个东西会像那样滑动
And if I tilt it this way, it'll slide over that way, and
如果我这样倾斜，它会那样滑动
I'll kind of, I can move it around that way.
我会那样，以那种方式移动它
All right, so how do we do that?
我们怎样做呢？
It's quite simple, actually.
实际上，这非常简单
First thing we need is a motion manager.
首先，我们需要 motionManager
And I told you that really wants to be a global thing
我告诉过你们，这个需要你们应用
in your app.
的全局东西
So I'm gonna put it in a global place,
我要把它放在全局的地方
which is my app delegate.
在我的 appDelegate 中
So I'm actually gonna go over to my app delegate and
实际上我要到我的 appDelegate，然后
get rid of all of this.
删掉所有这些
Okay?
And I'm gonna put a struct in here which
我要在这里添加一个结构体
I'm gonna call Motion and I'm going to have a static in here
我称之为 Motion，我要在这里有一个 static
which is the Manager equals CM Motion Manager.
manager 等于 CMMotionManager
Now look, I'm trying to type,
现在看看，我尝试输入
how come Xcode's not helping me here?
为什么 Xcode 在这里没有给我提示？
Well that's because the motion stuff is in a different
这是因为，motion 这个东西是一个不同的
framework that has to be imported, okay?
框架，需要被导入
So you have to import
所以你需要导入
core motion if you want to use any of that.
CoreMotion，如果你需要使用任何这些功能
As soon as you do that,
一旦你导入了
it's going to start escape completing here, all right?
它就开始在这里自动完成了
So I could put other things in this motion struct if I had,
我可以在这个 motion 中放其它东西，如果我有
maybe I wanted the rate at which I'm asking for
也许我想要让这个速度为全局的，
these things to be global.
我请求这些东西的速度
Maybe I'll put that as a constant in here as well.
也许这里我需要一个常量
But here I'm just gonna have the manager.
但这里我只是有一个 manager
So everybody in my app who's gonna use motion
所以在我的应用中的每个想要使用 motion 的人
needs to ask the app delegate for this motion manager.
需要向 appDelegate 请求这个 motionManager
And that way they'll all be using the same one, okay?
这样，他们就会使用同一个
Now I could have put this struct actually outside of
现在我可以把这个结构体放在
the app delegate and just said motion.manager and
appDelegate 的外部，然后让 motion.manager
had that be it.
等于它
But here I actually want to kind of explicitly make it
但这里，实际上我想明确的说清楚
clear that when you are in this app.
当你们在这个应用中
This is where this app gets its motion manager, 'kay?
这是这个应用获取它的 motionManager 的地方
And that might seem non-object-oriented,
这个看起来可能不那么面向对象
except that for again, this is a global resource.
除了这个，这个是全局的资源
We want to explicitly be sharing it, okay?
我想要明确的分享这个资源
So, that's why I put it in my AppDelegate.
这是为什么我把它放在我的 AppDelegate 中
So, now I can get it, here.
现在我可以获取它
I'm gonna say,
我要
let motionManager equal my AppDelegate.Motion.Manager.
let motionManger 等于我的 AppDelegate.Motion.Manager
Notice I made it capital because it's essentially
注意我让它大写，因为它本质上
a constant.
是一个常数
Motion.Manager is essentially a constant.
Motion.Manager 本质是个常量
And so I'm going set the update in a roll.
现在我设置更新
Well first of all I have to always check to make sure
首先我需要检查，确保
I have an accelerometer, it might be working on
我有一个加速计，它可能在一个
a device without it so I'm going to say.
没有它的设备工作，我要让
Motion manager, accelerometer available, sometimes people
motionManager，accelerometerAvailabel，有时人们
escape complete and they end up putting here active and
通过自动完成，他们把 activie 放在这里
they're like, why doesn't this work?
然后他们会很奇怪，为什么这不工作了
Okay, active is whether it's actively reporting
activie 是它是否积极报告
the accelerometer.
加速计
Available is whether the hardware is actually
Available 是这个硬件是否真的可用
available, so be careful there.
这里要小心
So if it's available then I'm just going to
如果它可用，然后我要开始
start getting updates.
获取更新
So again I'm gonna go wide here, motionManager,
再次，我要把这个变宽，motionmanager
startAccelerometerUpdatesToQu- eue, which is right here,
startAccelerometerUpdatesToQueue，这里
this one, okay.
这个
I have to specify what queue I want these updates to come on,
我要明确我想要这些更新发生在哪个队列中
so I'm gonna do NSOperationQueue mainQueue.
所以我需要 NSOperationQueue.mainQueue()
And, again, I'm gonna do the swift, put the last argument,
再次，我需要处理 swift，让最后一个参数
if it's a closure, outside of the parentheses thing.
如果它是一个闭包，在括号外面
I think there might be a way to do that with some clicking
我想可能有种点击魔法能做到这点
magic, but, anyway, here it is.
但，不管怎样，这就是了
Put that up here.
把这放在这里
Oh, I see why.
我明白为什么了
Okay.
So here is the closure, right here.
这里是闭包
And the argument is just the data, so I'm going to call
这个参数是 data，我将要使用这个
that one data, that's the accelerometer data.
data，这个是加速计的数据
And the error, I'm going to ignore the errors here.
这个 error，这里我要忽略错误
Probably you shouldn't ignore the errors, but
你们可能不应该忽略这些错误，但
in bouncer if I get an error I'm just not going to be
在 bouncer 中，如果我获取了一个错误，我不会设置
setting the gravity.
重力
But there's nothing for me to do, so
这里我也没什么可以做的
I'm just going to ignore that error, okay?
所以我要忽略这个错误
And, in fact, can I undo that?
但实际上，我可以撤销吗
And say error while you're already inside, okay?
当你们已经在里面，这个错误
So here I am.
我在这里
Now I just need to set the bouncer behavior's gravity
我需要设置这个 bouncer 的行为重力
equal to this accelerometer data that I got right here,
等于这里我获取的这个加速计的数据
which turns out to be very,
这个会非常
very simple since they're both in G.
非常简单，因为它们都在 G 中
They're in the same units, so it's easy to do.
它们有相同的单位，很好处理
I'm just going to say bouncer.gravity,
我要让 bouncer.gravity
which is my gravity behavior, .gravityDirection,
我的重力行为，.gravityDirection
which is a CGVector.
这个是一个 CGVector
Okay, so CGVector has doubles or floats.
CGVector 有 doubles 或 floats
The data from cell rom is actually doubles, not floats.
这个从单元 rom 中来的数据实际是 doubles，不是 floats
So I'm gonna set it as, this as double.
我要让它为 double
And it's just the data's acceleration in x.
它只是这个 data.acceleration.x
I'm gonna set that to be the gravity's acceleration,
我要让等于重力的加速度
essentially, in x.
根本是，x 值
And same thing for y, except for y, since zero is up and
y 也是一样的，除了 y，因为向上是0，然后
I want positive.
我想要正值
Gravity be down, I'm going to say minus data
重力向下，我需要负的 data.acceleration.y
acceleration y, okay?
So that's it,
这就是了
I've just set the acceleration due to gravity in the animator
我已经根据设备的加速度动画
to the acceleration of the device, okay?
设置重力加速度
Now one very important thing to do is,
现在一个非常重要的事情是
I'm starting updates.
我要开始更新
Never put code in the start update unless you put some
永远不要在开始更新中放代码，除非你要
code somewhere to stop it, okay?
在某些地方停止它
And the place to stop here,
在这里停止
since I'm doing this in the view did appear the obvious
既然我在 viewDidAppear 中做这个
place to stop it is view will disappear, okay?
停止它的地方是在 viewWillDisappear
So whenever this view goes off screen it will stop being
每次这个视图消失在屏幕上了，它将停止
the eyesore that I'm on which is exactly what I'm on.
我所在的碍眼的东西
So here I just say.
这里我只是表示
AppDelegate.Motion.Manager.st- opAccelerometerUpdates.
AppDelegate.Motion.Manager.stopAccelerometerUpdates
And if it comes back on screen,
如果它返回在屏幕上了
they'll start up again because it's view to appear, okay?
它们就又开始了，因为这个视图出现了
So if I had like a settings tab and I was going back and
如果我有一个设置选项卡，我来回出现
forth, it would turn it on and
它将打开和关闭它
off as we went back and forth, okay?
因为我反复出现和消失
So, see how this works.
看看这是如何工作的
All right, here's our bouncer, okay?
这是我们的 bouncer
And see how if I tilt it up, it goes this way.
如果我向上倾斜它会怎样，它会以这种方式跳动
And, now, I'm tilting it down, it's going down.
现在，我向下倾斜它，它会向下
Right, left, right?
向左，向右？
And that can even kinda use it to get it going faster and
通过加速度甚至可以让他们
faster by using the acceleration.
动的越来越快
Okay?
So you could imagine, I think we might even have made it
如果你们可以想象，我想我们甚至可以
extra credit, make it make your paddle in Breakout.
给它额外的学分，让它突破你们的桨
Be accelerometer based, right?
基于加速计
I get the paddle going there.
这里我有一个桨
Or make the bouncing ball in break out be effected by the.
或者让这个弹跳球被影响作出突破
I mean probably not this much effect.
我的意思是可能没这么多效果
You know, full gravitational effect but somewhat.
你们知道的，全重力影响，但有些
And if I set this down, although this table, I think,
如果我放下这个，平放在桌上，我想
is tilted a little this way, but.
它会这样一点点倾斜，但
See what happens?
看发生了什么？
You can see it settling down.
你们可以看到它安定下来了
It's setting down a little because my elasticity is not
它慢慢下来了，因为我的 elasticity
one, it's .85.
不是1，它是0.85
So all these bounce offs are not getting full effect.
但所有这个 bounce 关闭不会获取全部的效果
How do you slow this down, there, okay?
你们如何减慢这个下落？
Any questions about that?
有问题吗？
Now I was, I had on the agenda,
现在我得说下课程安排
which I obviously didn't even get close to talking to.
显然我不太想提这个
I knew it was going to be a time constraint,
但这里有时间限制
is persistence.
是持久性
I'm actually going to wait, and
实际上我将等
talk about that next Monday.
到下周一再谈这个
On Wednesday, we're going to do MapKits.
周三，我们要讲 MapKits
This Friday, the section is on AppleWatch.
这周五，是 AppleWatch 部分
Okay, so that should be a fun one.
这会非常有趣
And then next week, in addition to persistence,
下周，除了持久性
I'll be doing modal segueway.
我要做 modal segueway
Which you already pretty much know how to do because it's
这个你们已经非常清楚怎么做了，因为
just alerts for example, or just like mobile segueways.
它只是一个警告的例子，或就像手机 segueways
But also talk about the camera and then,
但也会谈谈相机，然后
if we have time next week, we'll talk
如果我们下周有时间，我们将
about internationalization of your apps.
讲解你们应用的国际化
It's really important to open your app up to large markets.
这对于你们应用打开一个更大的市场是非常重要的
And then settings,
然后设置
how to do settings inside the settings app, et cetera.
在应用设置中如何做设置，等等
So we got a lot of stuff to talk about.
我们有很多东西需要讲解
I'll trying to get to as much of it as I can in
我将在最后的几次课程中
the last few lectures here, all right?
尽可能多的讲解这些
If you have questions, I'm here as usual.
如果你们有问题，我像往常一样在这里
>> For more, please visit us at standford.edu.
更多的，请访问 standford.edu